4K资源来源:Hao4k影音
-专注4K家庭影音, 服务千万发烧友-
更多4K蓝光原盘:www.Hao4k.vip
在我年纪还轻、世故不深的时候…
In my younger and more vulnerable years...
我父亲曾教训我一句话
...my father gave me some advice.
他说“总要把人往最好的方面想”
"Always try to see the best in people," he would say.
由此，我一生待人接物宁可采取保留的态度
As a consequence, I'm inclined to reserve all judgments.
但是即便我也是有限度的
But even I have a limit.
彼时，我们所有人都沉溺于杯中物
Back then, all of us drank too much.
我们越想跟着这个时代
The more in tune with the times we were...
我们就越纵情沉醉
...the more we drank.
我们当中任何人也没创造出什么新的价值
And none of us contributed anything new.
当我回到纽约时，我感到厌世
When I came back from New York, I was disgusted.
我明白，卡拉威先生
I see, Mr. Carraway.
我讨厌周围一切人和事
Disgusted with everyone and everything.
我的这种反应只有对于一个人例外
Only one man was exempt from my disgust.
一个人？
One man?
卡拉威先生？
Mr. Carraway?
他是盖茨比
Gatsby.
他是您的朋友吗？
Was he a friend of yours?
他曾是…
He was...
我见过最有前途的人
...the single most hopeful person I've ever met.
并且我以后也不会再遇到他这样的人了
And am ever likely to meet again.
他对于生命前途的指望具有一种高度的敏感
There was something about him, a sensitivity.
像是…
He was like...
像是一具精密的仪器，能够探测一万英里以外的地震
He was like one of those machines that register earthquakes 10,000 miles away.
你在哪认识他的？
Where'd you meet him?
在一次…宴会上
At a...At a party...
在纽约
...in New York.
那是一九二二年的夏天
In the summer of 1922...
纽约的发展陷入了一种不正常的狂热
...the tempo of the city approached hysteria.
股票业务到达了巅峰
Stocks reached record peaks.
华尔街的金融业一度繁荣稳定
...and Wall Street boomed in steady golden roar.
宴会越来越大
The parties were bigger.
舞台越来越宽
The shows were broader.
建筑越来越高
The buildings were higher.
道德约束也越来越宽松
The morals were looser and the ban...
禁酒令没有取得预期效果
...on alcohol had backfired...
酒精越来越便宜
...making the liquor cheaper.
华尔街引诱着年轻人和野心家
Wall Street was luring the young and ambitious.
我便是其中之一
And I was one of them.
我在离城里二十英里的长岛上租了一所房子
I rented a house 20 miles from the city on Long Island.
我住在西卵
I lived at West Egg...
一所被遗忘的园丁小屋里
...in a forgotten groundskeeper's cottage...
被挤在暴发户们的豪华别墅之间
...squeezed among the mansions of the newly rich.
为了开始我的新事业，我买了十几本有关信贷和投资等方面的书籍
To get started, I bought a dozen volumes on credit, banking and investments.
对我而言完全是全新的领域
All new to me.
股票市场又创新高
The stock market hit another high.
大盘在上涨，上涨，不断上涨！
The market's moving up, up, up!
好的，当然，没有百分百确定，我不会花一分钱投资的
Well, of course, nothing is 100 percent. I wouldn't go investing every penny.
在耶鲁读书的时候，我曾梦想当一名作家
At Yale I dreamed of being a writer...
但我全然放弃了
...but I gave all that up.
阳光普照
With the sun shining...
绿树成荫
...and the bursts of leaves on the trees...
我本来打算
...I planned to spend...
将这个夏天用来学习
...the summer studying.
我本该好好学习的
And I probably would have...
要不是高墙那边巨大城堡里
...were it not for the riotous of amusements that beckoned...
那些喧嚣的娱乐招引着我
...from beyond the walls of that colossal castle
别墅的主人是一位我从未谋面的绅士
...owned by a gentleman I had...owned by a gentleman I had not yet met
他的名字叫盖茨比
...named Gatsby.
那么…
So...
…他是你的邻居
...he was your neighbor.
我的邻居
My neighbor.
是啊
Yeah.
当我回想起这段历史时，夏天才真正开始
When I think about it, the history of the summer really began...
那天晚上，我开车去我表妹黛西家赴宴
...the night I drove over to my cousin Daisy's for dinner.
她家住在海湾对面的东卵…
She lived across the bay in old moneyed...
传统富人区
, ,.East Egg-
她丈夫出身于美国最富有的家族之一
Her husband was heir to one of America's wealthiest families.
他的名字叫
His name...
汤姆·布坎南
...was Tom Buchanan
我们同在耶鲁读书的时候
When we were...
他就是一颗耀眼的体育明星了
...at Yale together, he'd been...
虽说现在他荣耀的时代一去不复返，他又开始
...a sporting star. But now his glory days were behind him and he...
- 沉迷于…  - 您的电话，布坎南先生
- ...contented himself with...  - Telephone, Monsieur Buchanan.
- 是我  - 嗯，其他事情
- It's me.  - ...other affairs.
我不是告诉过你么，不要往我家里打电话
I thought I told you not to call me here.
大财主
波阿斯！
Boaz!
大文豪
莎士比亚！
Shakespeare!
- 汤姆！哦！ - 哈哈哈！
- Tom! Oh!  - Ha-ha-ha!
- 你的小说写得怎么样了？ - 我现在在沃尔特·蔡斯的公司销售债券
- How's the great American novel coming?  - I'm selling bonds with Walter Chase's outfit.
我们晚饭后再谈，只有你和我，我们去城里
Let's say after dinner, you and I, we go into town.
- 我没法去  - 起去玩玩吧
- I can't.  - Catch up with the old wolf pack.
- 明天工作还有很多事情要做  - 胡说！就这么定了
- Big day on the job tomorrow.  - Nonsense! We're going.
这都是我在美国一流球队中获得的荣誉
First team, all-American.
瞧见没？
You see?
造就了今日的我
Made me who I am today.
森林山赛场上
Forest Hills.
出战威尔士亲王队，对方不堪一击
Played the Prince of Wales. What a sissy.
尼克，要是你足够优秀，人生由你主宰
Life is something you dominate, Nick! If you're any good.
噢！
Oh!
喔
Oh.
嘿
Hey.
亨利！你在哪里？
Henri! Where are you?
把门都关上
The doors! Close them.
- 抱歉  - 谢谢
- Sorry.  - Thank you.
是你么，亲爱的？
Is that you, my lovely?
黛西·布坎南，黄金女郎
Daisy Buchanan, the golden girl.
她身上散发出一股令人喘不过气的热情
A breathless warmth flowed from her.
好像这这个世界上她除了我以外
A promise that there was no one else...
不会这么热切地想见任何人
in the world she so wanted to see.
他们在芝加哥想我了没？
Do they miss me in Chicago?
是的，呃…呃，至少有一打朋友要我带信来问候你
Yes. Um, at least a dozen people send their love.
多好啊
How gorgeous.
他们想你想得好凄惨
They're absolutely in mourning.
- 他们不停地哭泣，是的  - 才不是呢
- They're crying. Yes.  - No.
- 我不相信你  - 甚至哭号
- I don't believe you.  - Wailing.
- 我不信你说的话  - 他们不断的哭号
- I don't believe you.  - They're screaming.
“黛西·布坎南，离开你我们就活不下去了！”
"Daisy Buchanan, we can't live without you!"
我高兴得瘫掉了
I'm paralyzed with happiness.
哇哦！
Whoa!
哇！哦！
Whoa! Oh!
乔丹·贝克，著名的高尔夫球手
Jordan Baker, a very famous golfer.
噢
Oh.
她是我见过的最令人惊慌的人
She was the most frightening person I'd ever seen.
呃，我…我曾在《体育生活》杂志封面上见到过你
Well, I...I've seen your face on the cover of Sporting Life.
尼克·卡拉威
Nick Carraway.
但我很喜欢看着她
But I enjoyed looking at her.
我从未在沙发上躺这么久
I've been lying on that sofa for as long as I can remember.
这个夏天我要撮合你俩，把你俩关在小房间里面
This summer I'll fling you two together. I'll push you into linen closets...
或者把你俩放在小船上往海里一推！
and out to sea in boats!
- 我什么也没听到  - 那么，尼克…
- I'm not listening to a word.  - So, Nick...
黛西告诉我
...Daisy tells me...
你从西卵来的
...that you're over in West Egg...
与那些只知道追名逐利的
Throwing your lot in with those social-climbing...
暴发户为邻
...primitive new-money types.
我的小棚屋只有纸盒那么大，租金一个月只要八十美元
My little shack's just a cardboard box at 80 a month.
你的生活真是可爱
Your life is adorable.
我在西卵认识些人
I know somebody in West Egg.
我在西卵
I don't know a single person...
一个人也不认识
...that side of the bay.
你一定知道盖茨比
You must know Gatsby.
盖茨比？
Gatsby?
哪个盖茨比？
What Gatsby?
夫人，晚餐准备好了
Madame, the dinner is servi.
你想听一听家庭秘密么？
Would you like to hear family secrets?
- 这正是我今晚来拜访的目的  - 是关于仆人的鼻子
- That's why I came over.  - It's about the butler's nose.
后来事情越弄越糟
Things went from bad to worse.
我最恨你用这个“横”字
I hate that word "hulking."
尼克，我听说你正准备和一个西部的姑娘结婚
Nicky, I heard a rumor that you were getting married to a girl out West.
完全是谣言
It's a libel.
- 我太穷了  - 他们一定是到了年纪了
- I'm too poor.  - They have to be old...
所以很快就会死的
...so they die quickly.
我们不能聊聊别的事儿么？
Can't we talk about something else?
什么都行，庄稼什么的
Anything. Crops.
跟你在一起我觉得我简直不够文明
You're making me feel uncivilized...
黛西
...Daisy.
还讲什么文明…文明社会已经破产了
Civilization's going to pieces.
你有没有看过一本书叫做《有色帝国的兴起》
Have you read The Rise of the Colored Empires...
作者是一个姓高达德的？大家都应当读一读
...by this fellow Goddard? Everybody ought to read it.
这本书大意是说
The idea is...
事实上，全要靠我们白种人，优越民族自己提防
...that it's up to us, the dominant race...
不然的话那些有色人种
...to watch out or these other races...
就会控制一切
...will have control of things.
汤姆近来常常研究学问，他读了许多深奥的书，书里尽是难懂的字眼
Tom's very profound lately. He reads deep books with long words in them.
这已经被证明了
It's been proved.
都是有科学根据的
It's scientific.
我们非打倒他们不可
We've got to beat them down.
布坎南公馆
Buchanan residence.
是修车厂的威尔逊先生
Monsieur Wilson, from the garage.
布坎南先生
Monsieur Buchanan.
失陪一下，我很快就回来
Excuse me, I'll be right back.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
- 呃，你刚提到的那位盖茨比先生…  - 我已经在处理了
- Well, this Mr. Gatsby you spoke of...  - I'm working on it.
- 他是我的邻居  - 嘘！别说话
- ...he's my neighbor.  - Shh! Don't talk.
我要听听看出了什么事
I wanna hear what happens.
我才不在乎你做了什么
I don't care what you do...
是出事了吗？
Something happening?
- 为什么这么说，我以为大家都知道了  - 好吧，我还不知道
- Why, I thought everybody knew.  - Well, I don't.
汤姆…
Tom's got some...
- 在纽约有了个女人  - 有一个女人？
- ...woman in New York.  - Got some woman?
这女的也真不识相，居然在吃饭的时候到电话到人家家里来，你看是不是岂有此理？
She might have the decency not to telephone at dinnertime. Don't you think?
- 是不是我管得太多了？ - 黛西，不要在客人面前大吵大闹
- Is that too much to ask?  - Daisy, don't create a scene.
尼克，我真喜欢你来我家做客
I love seeing you at my table, Nicky.
你使我想到一朵玫瑰花，的的确确一朵玫瑰花，你看是不是？
You remind me of a rose. An absolute rose...doesn't he?
那么晚饭后…
So after dinner...
我连玫瑰花的影子都没有
Well, I'm not even faintly like a rose.
尼克想要去城里
...Nick wanted to go into town.
是吧，尼克？去耶鲁俱乐部
Right, Nick? To the Yale club.
尼克，留下吧
Nicky, stay.
我明早还要上班
I have to work early.
胡说
Nonsense.
还有很多话要聊呢
There's so much to talk about.
我们只是去喝一两杯酒
It's just for a drink or two.
我们之中无人
None of us...
能忽略第五位客人
...could ignore that fifth guest's shrill...
尖锐的金属催促声
...metallic urgency.
- 尼克  - 怎么了？
- Nicky.  - What?
也没什么事，你知道的，我觉得事情已经一塌糊涂
It's just, well, you see, I think everything's terrible anyhow.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Really?  - Yes.
我什么地方也去过了，什么世面也见过了，什么事情也做过了
I've been everywhere and seen everything and done everything.
有一阵子我十分失落，尼克
I've had a very bad time, Nicky.
我对周遭一切都采取玩世不恭的态度
I'm pretty cynical about everything.
你的女儿，她应该会
Your daughter, I suppose she...
说话、吃饭，什么都会了吧？
...talks and eats and everything?
佩梅？
Pammy?
噢，是的
Oh, yes.
尼克，听我说，当她出生的时候
Listen, Nick, when she was born...
汤姆不知道跑到哪里
...Tom was God knows where...
去和谁鬼混去了
...with God knows whom.
我问护士
And I asked the nurse...
它是男孩还是女孩
if it was a boy or a girl.
然后她告诉我说是女孩
And she said it was a girl...
我哭了
...and I wept:
女的也好
"I'm glad it's a girl.
我盼望她长大了是个大傻瓜
And I hope she'll be a fool.
在这种世界上女孩子最好是傻瓜
That's the best thing a girl in this world can be.
一个年轻貌美的傻瓜
A beautiful little fool."
所有美好珍贵的事物总是消失得太快
All the bright, precious things fade so fast.
一去不复返
And they don't come back.
当我到家时
When I arrived home...
我看见一个人影
...I noticed that a figure...
出现在了我邻居的码头上
...had emerged on my neighbor's dock.
直觉告诉我那就是
And something told me it was...
盖茨比先生
...Mr. Gatsby.
他好像要将手伸向
He seemed to be reaching toward...
远处黑暗之中的什么东西…
...something out there in the dark.
一盏绿灯
The green light.
我不想再谈论这件事了，医生
I don't wanna talk about this, doctor.
那就写下来
Then write about it.
- 写下来？ - 是的
- Write about it?  - Yes.
我为什么要那么做？
Why would I do that?
你说过当你写作时
You said yourself writing...
会带给你慰藉
...brought you solace.
是的，好吧，但写作不会让其他人感到什么慰藉
Yeah, well, it didn't bring anyone else much solace.
我写的不好
I wasn't any good.
不会有人愿意读我的作品
No one need ever read it.
你可以烧掉它
You could always burn it.
我该写些什么呢？
What would I write about?
什么都行
Anything-
只要能让你感觉到轻松
Whatever brings you ease:
一段回忆
a memory...
一个想法，或者一个地方
...a thought, a place.
把它们写下来
Write it down.
一个地方
A place.
灰烬山谷是一个古怪的地方
The Valley of Ashes was a grotesque place.
西卵和纽约之间不到一半的路程，有一座垃圾场
New York's dumping ground halfway between West Egg and the city...
为纽约的繁荣提供过动力的煤块化为了粉尘
...where the burnt-out coal that powered...
这些粉尘居然堆成人形
...the booming golden city...
好似一个个满身灰土的人
...was discarded by men who...
走起路来影影绰绰
...moved dimly and already...
而且已经在尘土飞扬的空气中化为灰烬了
...crumbling through the powdery air.
这片不可思议的垃圾山谷
This fantastic farm...
被T.J.埃克尔堡医生盯着
...was ever watched by Dr. T.J. Eckleburg...
一名被遗忘的眼科医生目不转睛的望着这一切
...a forgotten oculist whose eyes brooded over it all...
就像上帝的眼睛一般
...like the eyes of God.
汤姆邀请我去纽约，显然是参加耶鲁俱乐部的午餐聚会
Tom had invited me to town, apparently for lunch at the Yale Club...
但是那天发生了一件意想不到的插曲
...but the day took an unexpected turn.
跟我来
Come on.
- 快跟我来！ - 你什么意思？
- Come on!  - What do you mean?
相信我！
Trust me!
- 我们要去做什么？ - 你们要去哪儿？
- What are we doing?  - Where are you going?
跳！
Jump!
- 你要做什么？ - 跳，快点！
- What are you doing?  - Jump, come on!
- 汤姆！ - 快点！
- Tom!  - Come on!
我的天啊
Oh, God.
汤姆，等下，等会儿，可以吗？
Tom, wait. Wait a second, would you?
主宰人生，尼克！
Dominate, Nick!
主宰人生！
Dominate!
你好，威尔逊
Hello, Wilson.
生意怎样？
How's business?
呵呵，不好不坏
Yeah, I can't complain.
呃…
Uh...
那么你打算什么时候
So when are you gonna...
- 把你那辆车卖给我？ - 噢，就快了，我叫车夫拿去修了，正在修理当中
- ...sell me that car?  - Oh, I've still got my man working on it.
好吧，他那个人做事相当慢，不是吗？
Yeah, well, he works pretty slow, don't he?
[你要是不高兴]我还是拿到别处去卖好了
Maybe I'd better sell it somewhere else.
哦，不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
我不是那个意思，我是说…
I wasn't saying that. I was...
如果是生意的话，你应该和我谈
If it's business, you should be talking to me.
拿凳子来
Get some chairs...
怎么还不去拿凳子，客人们都站着呢
...why don't you, so somebody can sit down.
哦，好的
Uh, sure.
好吧，我们来谈生意
Yeah, let's talk business.
没问题
Sure.
我去拿凳子来
I'll get the chairs.
梅朵
Myrtle...
- …你来招待一下？ - 快点
- ...why don't you entertain?  - Hurry up.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
布坎南先生
Mr. Buchanan.
要糖么？
Candy?
- 不用了，谢谢  - 不要么？
- No, thank you.  - No?
威尔逊太太，这是尼克·卡拉威
Mrs. Wilson, Nick Carraway.
噢
Oh.
荣幸之至
A pleasure.
尼克是名作家
Nick's a writer.
哦
Oh.
其实我是做债券生意的
I'm in bonds actually.
我想让你
I want you...
坐下一班列车
...get on the next train.
现在？
Now?
是的
Yes.
我们能带上狗么？
Can we get the dog?
- 到公寓里？ - 你说怎样就怎样
- For the apartment?  - Whatever you want.
嘿，布坎南先生
Hey, Mr. Buchanan!
要苏打水么？
You want a soda?
- 不用了  - 不要？
- I'm fine.  - No?
叫上你妹妹，她会喜欢他的
Call your sister. She'll like him.
不不，不用了，谢谢好意
No, no, no. That's all right, thank you.
认识凯瑟琳的人都说她长得好看
Catherine's said to be very good-looking by people who know.
噢，是吗，我就算了吧
Oh, really, I can't.
嘿
Hey-
你想让梅朵难堪么？
You wanna embarrass Myrtle?
这不礼貌
That's rude.
我就是凯瑟琳
I'm Catherine.
难道这里不是在举办宴会吗？
Ain't we having a party?
呃，我不太清楚…
Um, I'm not sure...
现在正是时候
...now's a good time.
我正打算走…其实房里还有人…
I'm just going. Actually, there are peop...
你好！
Hello!
噢，切斯特，这位一定就是那个表兄了
Oh, Chester, this must be the cousin.
- 哦，你看上去可真可爱噢  - 谢谢夸奖
- Oh, you are adorable.  - Oh, thank you.
切斯特·麦基，很高兴认识你
Chester McKee. Pleasure to meet you.
- 尼克·卡拉威  - 过来吧
- Nick Carraway.  - Come on...
- 你不喜欢我吗？ - 噢，嗨，一盆盆栽
- ...don't you like me?  - Oh. Heh. A plant.
梅朵！
Myrtle!
梅朵，朵朵！
Myrtle turtle!
我真的得走了
I really must go.
给大伙来杯喝的，以免无聊
Get everybody a drink before they fall asleep.
汤姆，我现在要走了
Torn, I'm just leaving now.
尼克
Nick.
等会
Wait.
- 我要走了，我要离开这里  - 胡说！
- I'm going. I've gotta get out of here.  - Nonsense!
继续进来和凯瑟琳聊聊
Go on in there and talk to Catherine.
我感觉不太舒服，黛西是我的表妹
I'm not comfortable. Daisy's my cousin.
听着，从大学起我就知道你的性子了，你只喜欢看
Listen, I know you like to watch. I remember that from college.
不不不，我没妄下判断
No, no, no, I don't make any judgment.
我们有一整个夏天的时间呢
We have all summer.
现在，你是想要坐在一旁当壁花少年还是跟我们一起玩？
Now, do you wanna sit on the sideline and watch, or do you wanna play ball?
一起玩呗
Play ball.
- 我们没法满足你么？ - 快来吧！
- Ain't we good enough for you?  - Come on!
来吧！快来吧
Come on! Come on.
他想要坐边上干看，哈？
He's gonna sit on the side and watch, huh?
还是他跟我们一起玩？
Or is he gonna play ball?
摘下帽子坐一会儿
Take off your hat and stay a while.
噢！嘿！尼克，这是麦基
Oh, hey, Nick. McKee...
- 是搞艺术的  - 我是摄影师
- ...is in the artistic game.  - Photography.
- 尼克也是搞艺术的  - 不是的
- Nick's artistic.  - No.
- 不，不是的  - 真的吗？
- No, no, no.  - Really?
- 我只是写过一点东西，不过…  - 真的吗？
- I write a little, but...  - Really?
你也住在长岛吗？
Do you live on Long Island too?
- 我住在西卵  - 我在那儿参加过一个宴会
- I live at West Egg.  - I was there at a party...
差不多一个月前…在一个姓盖茨比的家里，你认识他吗？
...about a month ago. A man named Gatsbys. Do you know him?
我住他家隔壁
I live right next door to him.
他是德国皇帝凯撒·威廉的亲戚
He's a cousin of Kaiser Wilhelm's.
- 你知道，邪恶的德国国王？ - 真的吗？
- You know, the evil German king?  - Really?
嘿，麦基！
Hey, McKee!
- 快来拍照  - 啊！
- Take a picture of that.  - Ah!
不要，我可不是那种模特
Don't, I'm not one of those models.
要是你喜欢可以随便照
You can if you want.
他们俩的婚姻都不美满…一个恨死了丈夫，一个恨死了妻子
Neither of them can stand the person they're married to.
她跟威尔逊的感情也不好吗？
Doesn't she like Wilson either?
他是个油腔滑调的
He's a greasy...
卑鄙人渣
...little scumbag.
不用了，谢谢，什么都不要我感觉就已经很好了
No, thanks, I feel just as good on nothing at all.
神经药物
Nerve pills.
我从皇后区的一个医生那里搞到的
I get them from a doctor in Queens.
你也想来一片么？
Do you want one?
不用了，我的神经很好，谢谢了
Oh, no. My nerves are fine, thanks.
我一生只喝醉过两次
I had been drunk just twice in my life.
那天下午就是第二次
And the second time was that afternoon.
那晚，在汤姆为梅朵准备的隐秘小公寓里
That night in the hidden flat that Tom kept for Myrtle...
我们在某种化学物质的催化下变得癫狂
we were buoyed by a sort of chemical madness.
一种自甘堕落的情绪如雷鸣般爆发在我们身上
A willingness of the heart that burst thunderously upon us all.
忽然间，我开始喜欢上纽约了
And suddenly, I began to like New York.
这比去耶鲁俱乐部好多了
This is better than the Yale Club.
我们这排灯火辉煌的窗户高高在这都市之上
High over the city, our yellow windows...
不知蕴藏着何等人生的秘密
must have contributed their share of human secrets to the casual watcher in the street.
而我脑海中也见到这么一位过客
And I was him too...
偶尔路过此地，抬头望望，不知所以
...looking up and wondering
我自己似乎又在里边又在外边
I was within and without
对这幕人生悲喜剧无穷的演变，又是陶醉又是恶心
enchanted and repelled by the inexhaustible variety of life.
你没有资格提黛西的名字！
You have no right to speak her name!
黛西，黛西，黛西！
Daisy, Daisy, Daisy!
- 你没有资格提黛西的名字！ - 我想提她的名字就提…
- You got no right to speak her name!  - I'll speak her name whenever...
- 哦我的天啊，你疯了！ - 你个臭婊子！
- Oh, my God, you are crazy!  - You whore!
他们得拘捕你！
They're gonna arrest you!
我不清楚我最后是怎么到家的
I have no clue how I got home.
但是我知道我是伴随着一种强烈不安的感觉醒来的…
But I do know that I awoke with the distinctly uneasy feeling
那就是…盖茨比正在看着我
...that Gatsby was watching me.
看着你？
Watching you?
是的，盖茨比常常看着我
Yes. Gatsby was always watching me.
那你是怎么知道的呢？
And how did you know that?
我收到了一份请柬
I got an invitation.
我是唯一一个被邀请的
I was the only one.
我是说，除了我以外
By which I mean,
造访他公馆的人没有真正收到过请柬的
no one except me ever received an actualinvitation to Gatsby's.
你知道的，纽约城的其他人都是不请自来
You see, the rest of New York simply came uninvited.
汽车载着全城的人蜂拥而至
The whole city packed into automobiles.
所有周末、每个周末都会在盖茨比公馆结束
And all weekend, every weekend ended up at Gatsby's.
吔！
Yeah!
我是说，来自各行各业的人
And I mean, everyone from every walk of life
以及来自纽约各地的人
...from every corner of New York City
都沉浸在这场万花筒似的狂欢中
This kaleidoscopic carnival...
- 这种气氛甚至都飘到盖茨比家大门外  - 别挡道！
- ...spilled through Gatsby's door.  - Out of the way!
我的邀请函，噢
My invitation. Oh.
先生，我的邀请函
Sir, my invitation.
这边请！
This Way!
嘿！
Hey!
满屋的
A caravanserai...
亿万富翁、花花公子出版商和他们的兔女郎
...of billionaire playboy publishers and their blond nurses.
斗富的女遗产继承人都齐聚盖茨比的海滩
Heiresses comparing inheritances on Gatsby's beach.
我的老板，沃尔特·蔡斯在轮盘赌桌上输钱
My boss, Walter Chase, losing money at the roulette tables.
报纸上漫谈栏的作家也在其中
Gossip columnists alongside...
黑帮和政府官员互相交换着联系电话
...gangsters and governors exchanging telephone numbers.
影星
Film stars...
百老汇导演
...Broadway directors...
卫道士
...morality protectors...
翘课的高中生
...high school defectors.
以及尤因克利普斯普林格，疑似的贝多芬后裔
And Ewing Klipspringer, dubious descendent of Beethoven.
你知道在哪能找到主人盖茨比么？我是他邻居
Do you know where I might find the host, Mr. Gatsby? I live next door.
盖茨比？
Gatsby?
我从没见到过盖茨比先生
I've never seen Mr. Gatsby.
为什么呢，因为没人见过
Why, no one has.
我百无聊赖
Alone and embarrassed
打算去喝个酩酊大醉
I decided to get roaring drunk.
哇哦
Wow.
我正在想也许你会来的
I thought I might see you here.
- 嗨  - 我记得…
- Hello.  - I remembered...
你就住在隔壁
...you live next door.
这就像个游乐园
It's like an amusement park.
借一步说话？
Shall we?
- 你收到邀请函了吗？ - 其他人都不是
- Did you get an invitation?  - People aren't...
收到请柬来盖茨比家的
...invited to Gatsby's.
好吧，我就是
Well, I was.
看上去我是唯一一个
Seems I'm the only one.
谁会是盖茨比呢？
Who is this Gatsby?
- 他在战争时期曾是名德国间谍  - 泰迪·巴顿
- He was a German spy during the war.  - Teddy Barton...
尼克·卡拉威
...Nick Carraway.
一名德国间谍？
A German spy?
不不不，他是凯撒皇帝的刺客
No, no, no. He's the Kaiser's assassin.
我听说他曾杀过个人
I heard he killed a man once.
- 没错  - 杀着玩，不收费
- True.  - Kills for fun, free of charge.
他显然比上帝还富有
He's certainly richer than God.
你不会真相信他杀过人吧，是吧？
You don't really believe he killed a man, do you?
我们去找到他吧，这样你就能亲口问他了
Let's go find him and you can ask him yourself.
女士们先生们，欢迎来到舞台
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome to the stage...
有请不可思议的
...the incredible...
百老汇当红舞星
吉尔达·葛雷小姐！
...Miss Gilda Gray!
查尔斯顿！
The Charleston!
至少我怀念
At least I miss
环世界旅行
Trips around the world
没有任何意义
Don't mean a thing
如果我不是你的女人
If I ain't your girl
我没有时间
I ain't got time
给你，亲爱的
For you baby
无论你是我的，或不是
Either you're mine Or you're not
盖茨比先生？
Mr. Gatsby?
甜心宝贝
Sweet baby
跟我来
Come on.
就在这里，就在此时
Right here, right now
然而你是搞错了
But you are mistaken!
我就是那位神秘的盖茨比先生
For I am the mysterious Mr. Gatsby.
你找不到他的，这所房子…
You won't find him.This house...
和其中的一切都是一个精心制作的伪装
and everything in it are all part of an elaborate disguise.
而盖茨比先生也是不存在的
But Mr. Gatsby doesn't exist.
呸，我见过他的
Phooey. I've met him.
真的吗？哪一个？
Really? Which one?
王子？
The prince?
间谍？
The spy?
杀人犯？
The murderer?
我还没发现有哪个真正了解关于盖茨比先生的真事
I cannot find anyone who knows anything real about Mr. Gatsby.
好吧，我并不关心
Well, I don't care.
他常常开大宴会
He gives large parties...
我最喜欢大宴会
...and I like large parties.
多么亲热，大家各管各的
They're so intimate.
小的聚会麻烦死了，一点都不得清净
Small parties, there isn't any privacy.
但刚才如果说的是真的
But if that's true...
那这些又为的是什么呢？
...what's all this for?
那，我亲爱的朋友
That, my dear fellow...
才是真正的问题
...is the question.
一点儿宴会永远
A little party never
不会让人无聊
Killed nobody
所以我们将要跳舞
So we gonna dance
直到我们终止
Until we drop
一点儿宴会永远不会
A little party never killed
让人无聊
Nobody
就在此处，就在此时，这是我们想要的一切
Right here, right now ls all we got
一点儿宴会
A little party
永远不会让人无聊
Never killed nobody
我能请你跳支舞么？
May I have this dance?
你个穷酸的小男人
You penniless pantywaist.
一点儿宴会永远不会
A little party never killed
哦，好棒
Oh, yeah.
让人无聊
Nobody
她是我的，卡拉威先生！
I'm stealing her away, Carraway!
- 女士们先生们  - 快点
- Ladies and gentlemen...  - Come on.
爵士音乐世界史总是伴随着烟火！
...a jazz history of the world and accompanying fireworks!
- 快点，尼克  - 好好打量一下你自己
- Come on. Nick.  - Look around you.
有钱的姑娘可不会嫁给穷小子的
Rich girls don't marry poor boys.
她是我的
She's mine.
你看上去很面熟
Your face is familiar.
你是不是打仗的时候在陆军第三师服役的？
Weren't you in the Third Division during the war?
- 哦，是的，我当时在第九营  - 我曾是七营的
- Oh, yes, the 9th Battalion.  - I was in the 7th.
我知道你看上去很面熟，玩的愉快，老兄？
I knew you looked familiar. Having a good time, old sport?
一切都太不可思议了
The whole thing's incredible.
我就住在隔壁
I live just next door.
他发给了我一份实实在在的请柬，看上去我是唯一的一个
He sent me an actual invitation. Seems I'm the only one.
我仍然还没见到盖茨比先生呢
I still haven't met Mr. Gatsby.
没有人见过他
No one's met him.
人们都说他是凯撒的表亲，又说他是魔鬼的表亲
They say he's third cousin to the Kaiser and second cousin to the devil.
恐怕是怪我不会做主人…
I'm afraid I haven't been a very good host...
老兄
...old sport.
你瞧
You see...
我就是盖茨比
...I'm Gatsby.
你是…
You're...
他那种笑容是你一辈子也难得遇见四五次的
His smile was one of those rare smiles that you may come across four or five times in life.
他这一笑向你表示他了解你，相信你
It seemed to understand you and believe in you...
并且如同你心里正想的那般
just as you would like to be understood and believed in.
对不起，老兄，我还以为你知道
Sorry, old sport. I thought you knew.
请只是…我不知道该说些什么
Please just...I don't know what to say.
请原谅我，我…  - 真的没关系
- Please forgive me. I've had...  - it's quite all right.
- 喝得太多了  - 什么事？
- ...so much to drink.  - Yes?
盖茨比先生…
Mr. Gatsby, sir.
芝加哥来电
Chicago on the wire.
我一会儿就进去
I'll be in in just a minute.
我准备明早试试我的新水上飞机
I'm taking my new hydroplane out in the morning.
你想和我一起来吗？
Would you like to go with me?
什么时间？
What time?
时间由你定
The time that suits you.
好吧，您太客气了
Well, that's very kind of you.
再次见到你真愉快，贝克小姐
Lovely to see you again, Miss Baker.
老兄，您要什么尽管开口
If there's anything that you want just ask for it, old sport.
对不起，一会儿再来奉陪
Excuse me. I will rejoin you later.
我以为他会是…
I expected him to be...
- 又老又胖？ - 是的
- Old and fat?  - Yes.
年轻人就不会冷静地四处漂泊
Young men don't just drift coolly out of nowhere...
还在长岛买下豪宅
...and buy a palace on Long Island.
他曾告诉过我他是牛津大学毕业的
He told me once he was an Oxford man.
可我不信他的话
However, I don't believe it.
为什么不信？
Why not?
我不知道，我只是不相信他在牛津念过书
I don't know. I just don't believe he went there.
对不起
I beg your pardon.
贝克小姐，盖茨比先生想和您讲两句
Miss Baker, Mr. Gatsby would like to speak to you.
单独地
Alone.
我？
Me?
是的，女士
Yes, madam.
尼克！
Nick!
我刚听到件震惊的事
I've just heard the most shocking thing.
你去哪儿了？车在等着了
Where have you been? The car's waiting.
简直太惊人了，一切都说的通了
Simply amazing. It all makes sense.
一切都说的通了
It all makes sense.
快来
Come on.
- 什么讲的通了？ - 所有事情！
- What makes sense?  - Everything!
快点，这太疯狂了！我们得离开这里
Come on, this is crazy! We gotta get out of here.
可是我刚才发誓不告诉别人
Here I am tantalizing you...
现在已经在逗你了
...when I swore I wouldn't tell.
赶紧告诉我吧
Just tell me.
哦，尼克，对不起，我发过誓的
Oh, Nick, I'm sorry, I swore.
我发过誓不会讲出来的
I swore I wouldn't tell.
抱歉让她离开你，老兄
Sorry to keep her from you, old sport.
- 啊  - 别忘了
- Ah.  - Don't forget...
我们明天要去水上飞机
...we're going up in that hydroplane tomorrow.
好的
Yes.
盖茨比先生，阁下
Mr. Gatsby, sir...
- 费城来电  - 知道了
- ...Philadelphia on the phone.  - Yes.
晚安，老兄
Night, old sport.
晚安
Good night.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
汽油不够了吗？
You run out of gas?
尼克！记得来看我！
Nick! Come and see me!
下周我们一起喝茶
We'll have tea next week.
电话联系簿里能找到我的联系方式
I'm in the phone book.
我会打给你的
I'll call you up.
我们开上了水上飞机
Well, we rode in the hydroplane.
又去了两次他的宴会
And I attended two more of his parties.
甚至去享用他的海滩
Even made use of his beach.
但你要知道，医生，我意识到…
But you know, doctor, I realized...
我对于盖茨比先生根本不甚了解
...that I knew absolutely nothing about Gatsby at all.
直到…
Until....
这部车子漂亮吧，老兄？你没有看见过我这部车吗？
It's pretty, isn't it, old sport? Haven't you ever seen it before?
全手工制作
It's all a custom job.
增压式发动机
Supercharged engine.
穿好衣服
Get dressed.
我们去城里吃午饭
We're going to lunch.
- 很棒吧  - 是啊
- Oh, well.  - Yeah.
喂，老兄…
Look here, old sport.
你对于我这个人到底怎么看？
What is your opinion of me, anyhow?
- 我的看法？ - 是的，你的看法
- My opinion?  - Yes, yes, your opinion.
我不希望你听了那些怪诞不经的闲话
I don't want you to get the wrong impression...
对我产生不好的印象
...from all these bizarre accusations you must be hearing.
我敢保证那都是一派胡言，你听过那些故事吧？
A pack of lies, I guarantee. You've heard the stories?
噢
Oh.
上帝做见证，我要跟你说老实话，绝对的真实
I will tell you God's truth. God's truth about myself.
我生在中西部有钱人家
I am the son of very wealthy people from the Middle West.
亲人们早已不幸去世
Sadly, all of them are dead.
我在美国长大
I was brought up in America...
但是在牛津大学受的教育
...but educated at Oxford...
因为我们家世世代代
...because all my ancestors...
都是在牛津念书的，这是我们家里的传统
...have been educated there for years. It's a family tradition.
他说话的方式
The way he spoke.
难怪会让人们觉得他在说谎
No wonder people thought he was lying.
我的家人去世后，我继承了一大笔遗产
After my family died, I ran into a great deal of money.
后来我就在欧洲各国首都去住了一阵，像王子那样阔绰…
After that, I lived like a young prince in all the capitals of Europe.
噢，欧洲
Oh, Europe.
是的，欧洲
Yes, Europe.
…巴黎、威尼斯[不是首都]、罗马、维也纳
Paris, Venice, Rome, Vienna...
苏黎世[不是首都]、赫尔辛基
...Zurich, Helsinki...
莫斯科、伊斯坦布尔[不是首都]…
...Moscow, Istanbul...
到处收藏珠宝…
...collecting jewels...
我尤其喜欢红宝石…
...chiefly rubies...
打打猎
...hunting big game...
学学画…不过是为自己消遣而已，同时忘掉一些伤心事…
...painting a little, things for myself only. Trying to forget something sad...
他这么一说
Just when I thought...
就更让我觉得他是信口开河了
...it couldn't be any more fantastical...
- 再后来，老兄，欧战爆发了  - 他成为了
- Then came the war, old sport.  - ...he became...
一名战斗英雄，单枪匹马对抗德国军队
...a war hero, single-handedly defeating the German army.
在阿贡森林一役，我率领两个机关枪营到前线去…
In the Argonne Forest, I took two machine gun detachments so far...
当时敌众我寡，敌方人数是我们的五倍…
We were outnumbered 5 to 1.
我们位置全无掩护，两边半英里路之内步兵都赶不上来…
There was a half a mile gap...on either side.
我们苦战两天两夜
There wasn't a single German soldier left standing.
一百三十名士兵，十六挺刘易斯式轻机关枪
We stayed there two days and two nights.Saw were piles of dead.
把德国兵杀得一个不剩
One hundred and thirty men with only 16 Lewis guns.
联盟国每一国政府都颁给我奖章
Every Allied government gave me a medal.
即使是门的内哥罗
Even Montenegro.
给
Here.
这就是门的内哥罗给我的奖章
That's from Montenegro.
“颁赠杰·盖茨比少校‘英勇无双’”
"Major Jay Gatsby for valor extraordinary."
- “英勇无双”  - 没错
- Valor extraordinary.  - That's right.
这里还有一件我老是随身带的纪念品，牛津大学的照片
And this is something I always carry with me, a souvenir of Oxford days.
是在三一书院校园里拍的…
That was taken in Trinity quad. The man on my left...
- 我左边的那个现在是唐卡斯特伯爵  - 我还能说什么呢？
- ...is now the Earl of Doncaster.  - What could I say?
照片毋庸置疑是真实的
The photograph was undoubtedly authentic.
但他说的全都是真的吗？
Could it all be true?
当然，你不需要相信我的话，老兄
Of course, you don't need to take my word for it, old sport.
午饭时，我会把你介绍给纽约最著名的生意人之一
At lunch, I'm going to introduce you to one of New York's most distinguished businessmen...
我的好友…迈尔·吴夫山
...a Mr. Meyer Wolfshiem, my good friend.
他会让你确信我所述是真实的
He will confirm all I have told you...
- 还会为我的人格担保  - 没这个必要的
- ...and vouch for my good character.  - That's not necessary.
噢，还是有的
Oh, but it is, though.
我觉得你该多了解一些我的事，我不希望你认为我是…
I thought you ought to know something about my life. I didn't want you to think I was...
好吧
Well...
我不希望你把我当做一个可有可无的人
...I didn't want you to think I was some nobody.
你瞧，老兄，我今天有一件要紧的事要请你帮忙
You see, old sport, I'm going to make a very big request of you today.
一件要紧的事？
A big request?
是的
Yes.
贝克小姐会解释所有事情的
Miss Baker will explain everything...
在今天下午你和她喝茶的时候
...when you take her to tea this afternoon.
乔丹？她想要做什么？
Jordan? What's she got to do with it?
好吧，我向你保证
Well, I assure you...
没有任何圈套
...it's nothing underhand.
贝克小姐是个诚实的女运动员
Miss Baker's an honest sportswoman. She wouldn't do...
她不会做什么不正当的事
...anything that wasn't all right.
靠边停车！
Pull over!
- 靠路边停车！ - 好吧，老兄，好吧
- Pull over to the curb!  - All right, old sport. All right.
原来是您！
Right you are!
下次就认得了
I'll know you next time...
盖茨比先生！
...Mr. Gatsby!
- 实在抱歉  - 谢谢
- Excuse me.  - Thank you.
你的牛津老朋友之一么？
One of your old Oxford pals?
我帮过警察厅长的忙
Well, I was able to do the commissioner a favor once.
他每年都给我寄来圣诞贺卡
He sends me a Christmas card every year.
我猜想他午餐也会出席的，嗯哼
I imagine he'll be at lunch too. Heh.
这时候
By the time...
我们到了桥上，我感到难以言状困惑
...we reached the bridge, I was impossibly confused.
我不知道该作何感想
I didn't know what to think.
从皇后大桥上瞻望纽约市
But the city seen from the Queensboro Bridge...
永远好像是初次看见一样
...is always the city seen for the first time...
一幅奇景…充满了世界上所有的神秘与瑰丽
...in its first wild promise of all the mystery and the beauty in the world.
任何事都可能发生
Anything can happen.
“一开过这顶桥什么事都可能发生”
"Now that we've slid over this bridge,"
我心想
I thought.
没啥稀奇
Anything at all.
连盖茨比这种人物也会发生
Even Gatsby could happen.
是的，当然
Yes, absolutely.
哦！
Oh!
啊！
Ah!
我的孩子！
My boy!
迈尔，迈尔，迈尔
Meyer, Meyer, Meyer.
嗯，闻上去好极了
Mm. Smell so good.
- 看看你！ - 看看你
- Look at you!  - Look at you.
这是卡拉威先生，这位是我的好朋友，迈尔·吴夫山先生
Mr. Carraway, this is my good friend, Mr. Meyer Wolfshiem.
荣幸之至
A wonderful pleasure...
- 卡拉威先生  - 很高兴认识您
- ...Mr. Carraway.  - My pleasure.
我知道关于你的一切
I know all about you.
- 哦，是吧  - 是啊！盖茨比先生总是说起你
- I see.  - Yes! Mr. Gatsby's always talking about you.
是吗？
Really?
借一步聊？
Shall we?
来吧
Come.
一起来吃午餐吧
Join us for a little lunch.
- 把手拿开  - 出去！给我滚出去！
- Hands off!  - Out! Out you go!
放开我！
Get off me!
告诉沃尔特·蔡斯闭上他那狗嘴
Tell Walter Chase he keeps his mouth shut...
不然他一分钱也拿不到
...or he doesn't get a penny.
我们等一下再聊
We'll talk about that later.
高杯酒指苏打水之类的碳酸饮料兑酒类饮料的鸡尾酒
要高杯酒吗，盖茨比先生？
Highballs, Mr. Gatsby?
没错，高杯酒
Highballs it is.
- 好的  - 照顾好我的朋友
- All right.  - You take care of my friend.
什么风把你吹来了？
Look who's here.
看到这对拳头了吗？
You see these fists?
他就是下一个重量级的冠军
He's the next heavyweight champion.
向你的老板转达我的敬意
Pay my respects to your boss.
嘿，杰！
Hey, Jay!
你被捕了！哈哈哈！
You're under arrest! Ha-ha-ha!
你要当心点了哦你可已经是个真正的探长了，厅长大人
You be careful, now. You're turning into a real jazz hound, commissioner.
嘣，嘣！
Bang,bang!
- 那位是警察厅长  - 盖茨比先生
- That's the commissioner.  - Mr. Gatsby...
您的位子已经准备好了
...your table is ready.
- 盖茨比！ - 见到你真好
- Gatsby!  - Good to see you.
是啊，简直太好了
Yeah, that's fantastic.
在那些桌子边上你可要小心点哦
You be careful at those tables now...
参议员先生
...senator.
我赌你赢，杰！
I'll put a bet on for you, Jay!
我点了龙虾
We'll have the lobster.
搭配松露，还有些新鲜蔬菜
It's decorated with truffles and fine herbs.
那么
So...
债券生意怎么样了，卡拉威先生？
...how is the bond business, Mr. Carraway?
挺好的，谢谢
Fine. Thank you.
我听说你要找一个
I understand you're looking for...
- 干系做生意  - 不不不不
- ...a business connection.  - No. No, no, no.
不不不
No, no, no.
不是他，迈尔
This isn't the man, Meyer.
这位是我之前
This is the friend...
跟你提过的朋友
...that I told you about.
噢，真不好意思
Oh, I beg your pardon.
我认错人了
I had a wrong man.
容我离开一下，我得去
If you'll excuse me, I have to make...
打个电话
...that call.
手气怎么样，参议员先生？
Any luck, senator?
真是一表人才
What a gentleman.
出身于中西部最鼎盛的家族
From one of the finest families in the Midwest.
可惜，他家就剩他一个了
Sadly, all dead now.
打完仗之后，我有一个机会跟他相识
When I first made the pleasure of Mr. Gatsby's acquaintance just after the war...
我就知道我发现了一位上等人家出身的子弟
...I knew I'd discovered a man of fine breeding.
绝对的战争英雄
A war hero.
拥有那么多的勋章
Such medals.
而且…
And...
还是…
牛津大学的毕业生
...an Oxford man.
你知道牛津大学吧？
You know Oxford?
是的，我听说过
Yes, I've heard of it.
然后你就会发现，在已婚妇女眼里
Then you'd know that when it comes to married women...
他这样的男人是挺可靠的
...a man like this can be trusted.
跟一个你这样的朋友在一起
With a friend...with someone like you...
他绝不会多看你老婆一眼
...he'd never so much as look at your wife.
我还没结婚呢
I'm not married.
但是你在华尔街工作，不是吗？
But you work on Wall Street, right?
是啊
Yes.
啊
Ah.
看到我的领带别针没？
Looking at my tiepin?
这是精选的真人板牙
Finest specimen of human molar.
先生们
Gentlemen.
感觉不错吧？
Everything all right?
挺好，挺好，我们…
Yes! Yes. We...
我们刚刚在讨论别人的老婆
We were just talking about other people's wives.
别人的老婆？
Other people's wives?
- 对  - 是吗？
- Yes.  - Really?
好吧，我已经没事了
Well, my work here is done.
你们再坐一会儿，谈谈体育，谈谈女人
I'm going to leave you gentlemen to talk about your sports and your women.
别人的老婆
Other people's wives.
你们好啊，女士们
Hello, ladies.
噢～
Ooh.
他到底是干什么的？
Who is he, anyhow?
演员？
An actor?
你是说迈尔·吴夫山？
Meyer?
不，不是，他是个开赌场的
No, no. He's a gambler.
一九一九年世界棒球联赛舞弊案的主使人就是他
He's the man who fixed the 1919 World Series.
舞弊案的主使人？
Fixed it?
是的，舞弊案的主使人
Fixed it.
他怎么会做出这样的事？
Well, how'd he manage that?
我猜他只是看到了机会
Saw the opportunity, I suppose.
他是个绝顶聪明的人
He's a very smart man.
好吧，老兄，我想说说贝克小姐还有我请你帮忙的事…
Now, old sport, about Miss Baker and that request we spoke of.
尼克？尼克！
Nick? Nick!
汤姆！这么巧碰到你了！
Tom! Funny seeing you!
- 最近怎么样？ - 挺好的
- How have you been?  - Yeah.
- 那就好  - 黛西气得要命
- Good.  - Nick, Daisy is furious...
- 因为你没有给她打电话  - 嘿
- ...that you haven't called.  - Hey...
盖茨比先生，这位是布坎南先生
...Mr. Gatsby, this is Mr. Buchanan.
很高兴认识您
It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance.
嗯
Yeah.
从没想过会在这个地方遇到你
Never would have expected to find you in this temple of virtue.
我正在跟盖茨比先生一起吃饭
I was having lunch with Mr. Gatsby.
- 先生，您需要我帮忙吗？ - 我在找乔丹·贝克
- Can I help you, sir?  - Jordan Baker...
那个有名的体育明星，高尔夫球手…哦，我看到了
...the famous sporting star? The golfer? I see.
我看到她了，谢谢
I've spotted her. Thank you.
原来你在这
There you are.
你和盖茨比到底在玩什么把戏？
What game are you and Gatsby playing at?
- 这位先生要一起…？ - 打扰一下
- The gentleman will be joining...?  - Excuse me.
- 尼克，拜托…  - 一切都发生得那么诡异
- Nick, please.  - It's all rather strange.
他用他的豪华小汽车来接我
He picks me up in his fancy car.
- 他在谈…  - 嘘…
- Going on about...  - Keep your...
- 他的经历  - 小声点
- ...his life.  - ...voice down.
大家都能听到你在说什么
People can hear you.
这到底是帮哪门子的大忙？
What is this enormous request?
他想让你邀请黛西一起喝茶
He wants you to invite Daisy to tea.
黛西？
Daisy?
和盖茨比
And Gatsby.
为什么？
Why?
我也不知道该从何说起
I don't quite know where to start.
在那天晚上，我没有料到我会遇到盖茨比
You see, I didn't realize until the other night that I've met Gatsby.
那是在五年前，路易斯维尔
Five years ago. In Louisville.
那天，我脚上穿着一双新的英格兰高尔夫球鞋
It was the day I got my new English golf shoes.
黛西是泰勒军营最受军官们欢迎的社交小姐
Daisy was by far the most popular girl with the officers from Camp Taylor.
你好啊，乔丹
Hello, Jordan.
有一位军官和她同坐在车里，他就是盖茨比
One of them was in the car with her. It was Gatsby.
他两眼盯着她看
The way he looked at her is the way...
那种陶醉的样子每个女孩都巴不得有人这么看她
...all girls want to be looked at.
然后呢…
So...
告诉我之后发生什么事了
...tell me what happened.
我也不知道
Well, I don't know.
冲啊！
Charge!
盖茨比去前线了
JORDAN. Gatsby was sent off to war.
当战争结束时，黛西也在等待
When the war ended, Daisy waited...
但因为一些不为人知的原因，盖茨比没能回来
But for some unknown reason, Gatsby couldn't return.
一年后，芝加哥的汤姆·布坎南把她拐走了
A year later, Tom Buchanan of Chicago swept in and stole her away.
他送给了她一串价值三十五万美金的珍珠项链
He gave her a string of pearls worth $350,000.
但就在婚礼那天早上
But the morning of the wedding...
- 黛西收到了一封信  - 告诉他们
- ...Daisy received a letter.  - Tell them...
黛西改了主意啦！
...Daisy's changed her mind!
- 这是什么？ - 黛西，别闹了
- What is this?  - Daisy, please!
- 给我  - 不！
- Hand it to me!  - No!
让我一个人待着！
Leave me alone!
乔丹，这事不能让任何人知道！
Jordan, no one must know about this.
- 信里写的什么？ - 不知道
- What was in the letter?  - I don't know.
她不会告诉我的
She wouldn't tell me.
但是一切都太晚了
But it was too late.
那天下午五点整，黛西·菲嫁给了汤姆·布坎南
That day at 5:00, Daisy Fay married Tom Buchanan.
结婚时的场面阔绰是路易斯维尔从来没有见过的
...with more pomp and circumstance than Louisville had ever seen.
恭喜你，布坎南先生！
Congratulations, Mr. Buchanan!
等他们蜜月旅行回来，我在圣巴巴拉见到他们
After the honeymoon, I saw them in Santa Barbara.
我的印象是我从来没见过一个女孩跟他丈夫那么要好的
Well, it was touching, really. I'd never seen a girl so in love with her husband.
一周后，汤姆出了车祸
A week later, Tom crashed his car.
跟他一起出事的还有一个圣巴巴拉饭店里打扫房间的女佣
The girl with him was a chambermaid at the Santa Barbara Hotel.
这条新闻登了报
It got into all the papers.
- 真是无巧不成书  - 此话怎讲？
- It's a strange coincidence.  - What is?
盖茨比的房子正好在黛西家的岸对面
The fact that Gatsby's house is just across the bay.
这绝对不是凑巧
It's no coincidence.
盖茨比就是为了能离黛西近点才买的那幢房子
He bought that house to be near her.
他摆出这样阔绰的场面，指望哪天晚上她可能也会来他家参加一次宴会
He threw all those parties hoping she'd wander in one night.
他经常到处打听黛西，一直等问到了我
He constantly asked about Daisy. I was just the first person that knew her.
他所做的一切都是为了一个五年未谋面的姑娘
All that for a girl he hasn't seen in five years.
而现在他就只是希望我可以邀请她一起过去喝茶
And now he just wants me to invite her over to tea.
他真是羞涩
The modesty of it.
有点难以置信
Kind of takes your breath...
- 难道不是吗？ - 晚上好，甜心，你们要去哪里？
- ...away, doesn't it?  - Evening, sweethearts. Where are you kids going?
- 长岛，谢谢  - 那你觉得…
- Long Island, please.  - And you think...
呃…我是说…黛西愿意见盖茨比吗？
...I should. I mean, does Daisy want to see Gatsby?
我们的计划是不让她知道
She's absolutely not to know.
表面上只是你请她来喝茶
You're supposed to invite her over...
盖茨比则可以装作是恰好经过你家
...so he can happen to pass by.
我当时感觉很纠结…
I remember feeling torn.
到底应不应该带我的表妹黛西…一个有夫之妇
Was it right to bring my cousin Daisy, a married woman...
…去见一个我都不熟知男人？
...together with a man I hardly knew?
当我回到家时，看到盖茨比家的从楼顶到地窖上上下下灯火辉煌
When I returned home, Gatsby's was lit from tower to cellar...
犹如又一个喧嚣的宴会
...as if for another wild party.
可是再一听一点声音也没有
But there wasn't a sound.
- 谢谢你  - 祝您有一个美妙的夜晚
- Thank you.  - Have a good night.
你家灯点得像开博览会一样
Your place looks like the World's Fair...
科尼岛：美国纽约市布鲁克林区南部海滩疗养和娱乐中心
或者说是科尼岛
...or Coney Island.
- 像吗？ - 像极了
- Does it?  - Yes.
呃，我刚才只是在看着这些房间…
Well, I've just been glancing into some of the rooms
老兄，咱们到科尼岛海边去逛逛，好吗？我开车去
. What do you say we go to Coney Island? We could take my car.
噢，呃，今天太晚了
Oh, uh, it's too late tonight.
我们可以一头扎进游泳池里，我已经一整个夏天都没有游泳了
We could take a plunge in the pool. I haven't made use of it all summer.
我得上床睡觉了
I must go to bed.
好吧
All right.
玩的开心点
Happy to do it.
我会打电话给黛西
I'm going to call Daisy and...
- 邀请她来喝茶  - 太好了
- ...invite her to tea.  - That's all right...
- 你哪天方便？ - 你呢，你哪天方便？
- What day would suit you?  - What day would suit you?
我不想太麻烦你
I don't want to put you to any trouble.
后天怎么样？
Day after tomorrow all right?
后天？
Day after tomorrow?
呃，我…我还得…
Well, I...I'd...
我要把草坪修剪一下
See, I'd want to get the grass cut.
呃…
Uh...
喂，我说老兄
Well, look here, old sport.
你收入不太多吧？
You don't make much money, do you?
- 不太多  - 请原谅我的唐突…
- Not really.  - If you'll forgive me...
你明白，我有一点小生意，附带做一点小生意…
You see, I happen to run a little business on the side. A sort of sideline.
你懂我的意思？你是做股票生意的
You understand what I'm saying, right? You do sell bonds...
是不是？
...don't you, old sport?
- 学学而已  - 正好
- I'm trying to.  - Right.
说起来倒是一件相当机密的事
Well, happens to be a rather confidential sort of thing...
你可以赚不少外快
...but you might make a nice bit of money.
- 多谢，我已经够忙的了，不能再考虑什么别的工作  - 你别误会…
- No, thank you. I have my hands full.  - You wouldn't have to do...
这个生意和吴夫山不相干，我保证
...any business with Wolfshiem, I assure you.
杰，举手之劳，何足挂齿
It's a favor, Jay. Just a favor.
是的，乐意之至
Yes. Happy to do it.
- 这么说你愿意了？ - 是的
- Favor?  - Yes.
嗯
Hm.
好的，晚安
Well, good night.
晚安
Good night.
早上好
Good morning.
有一家报纸说今天的雨四点左右会停
One of the papers says they thought the rain would stop about 4.
大概是《纽约日报》说的
I think it was the...I think it was the Journal.
啊
Ah.
进去往右，先生们，往右
Just in to the right, gentlemen. To the right...
放在客厅里，谢谢
...in the living room. Thank you.
一切都弄妥当了吗？
Is everything all right?
你是不是指草坪？看上去挺好的
The grass looks fine, if that's what you mean.
草坪？
Grass?
什么草坪？
What grass?
我买了蛋糕
I bought cakes.
你…把需要的都准备好了吗？
Have you...Have you got everything you need?
要不然再来点花？
Perhaps more flowers.
我觉得他们干的不错，你觉得呢？
I think they did a fine job, don't you?
很美
Beautiful.
你会不会觉得太多了？
You think it's too much?
唔，我觉得这是你想要的
Uh, I think it's what you want.
我也是这么想的
I think so too.
我不能在这里等一整天
I can't wait all day.
我要回家了
I'm leaving.
别犯傻了，还有两分钟就四点了
Don't be silly. It's two minutes to 4.
我看没有人会来喝茶了！太晚…
No one's coming to tea! It's too...
是她！
It's her!
我最最亲爱的表哥啊，你真的是住这里吗？
Is this absolutely where you live, my dearest one?
是啊，很适合我
Yes, it suits me.
这是不是情人的幽会，不然的话为什么我非得一个人来？
Why did I have to come alone? Are you in love with me?
噢，这是卡拉威城堡的秘密
Oh, it's the secret of Carraway Castle.
- 叫你的司机走远一点  - 一个小时后来接我，福第
- Tell your chauffeur to go far away.  - Come back in an hour Ferdie.
他的名字叫福第
His name is Ferdie.
噢
Oh.
噢，我的天啊
Oh. My goodness.
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
你…你是不是洗劫了花房啊？
You...Did you ransack a greenhouse?
他肯定是爱上我了
He is in love with me.
帮我把帽子拿着？
Would you?
真是怪事…
That's funny.
什么怪事？
What's funny?
啊
Ah.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我真的高兴极了，又见到你
I'm certainly glad to see you again.
嗨，我…
Hi. I'm...
能再见到你，我也很高兴
I'm certainly glad to see you, as well.
我们…我们…我们以前见过
We've...We've...We've met before.
我马上就去找个人来修
I'll have someone come repair this immediately.
对不起…你那座钟
Sorry about the clock.
- 没关系…很旧的钟  - 很可爱
- That's an old clock.  - Lovely, though.
- 很可爱的钟  - 是的
- A lovely clock.  - Yes.
我们有好多年没见面了
We haven't met for many years.
到今年十一月整整五年
Five years next November.
喝茶吗？
Tea?
- 好的，谢谢，老兄  - 谢谢
- Yes, thank you, old sport.  - Thank you.
- 加柠檬还是糖？ - 都不要
- Lemon or sugar?  - Neither.
原味的，谢谢
Plain. Thank you.
我突然有点急事
I just have to pop...
- 需要进城里一趟  - 进城？
- ...into town.  - Town?
我很快就回来
I'll be right back.
尼克，我有句话要跟你说
Nick, I've gotta speak to you.
- 好的，我一会就回来了  - 天呐
- Yes. I'll be right back.  - God.
这件事做错了，真是大错，特错！
This was a mistake. This was a terrible, terrible mistake.
没什么错，你不过是不好意思而已，黛西也有点不好意思
You're just embarrassed. Daisy's embarrassed too.
- 她不好意思？ - 是啊
- She's embarrassed?  - Yes.
跟你一样不好意思
Just as much as you are.
- 声音不要那么大  - 嘿
- Don't talk so loud.  - Hey.
你简直像一个小孩，不但如此，你还很没有礼貌
You're acting like a little boy. You're being rude. Daisy's...
- 黛西一个人坐在里面  - 嘘
- ...in there all alone and you're...  - Shh.
时至今日，回顾我的故事
Looking over my story so far...
我忆起这是那个夏天我第二次守护着别人的秘密
...I'm reminded that for the second time that summer I was guarding other people's secrets.
又一次，我既置身事内又置身事外
Once again, I was within...and without.
嗯哼
Ahem!
雨停了
It's stopped raining.
是啊
Yes.
雨停了，不是吗？
It has, hasn't it?
你觉得那边如何，黛西？
What do you think of that, Daisy?
过来看看
Come look.
噢，尼克，真有意思
Oh, Nicky. How funny.
看，那是我家
Look, it's my house.
就在海湾对面
Just there across the bay.
我知道
I know.
从我家也能看到同样的景色
I have the same view from my place.
你家在哪？
Where's your place?
尼克…
Nick...
我想邀请你和黛西到我家来，我想带她参观参观
...I want you and Daisy to come over to my house. I'd like to show her around.
你真的要我也来吗？
You sure you want me to come?
绝对没问题，老兄
Absolutely, old sport.
当然！
Absolutely.
雷德纳，开门
Ladner, open the gates.
开门！
Open the gates!
我从诺曼底的一座城堡里弄来的大门
I had the gates brought in from a castle in Normandy.
噢，杰
Oh, Jay.
- 太宏伟了！ - 你喜欢吗？
- It's so grand.  - You like it?
喜欢得很
I love it.
但是我不懂你怎么能一个人住那么大的房子
But how do you live here all alone?
哦，不是这样的
Well, I don't.
我一天到晚都有客人，都是一班有意思的名流
I keep it always full of interesting, celebrated people.
跟我来
Come with me.
这房子看起来不错，是吧？
The house looks well, doesn't it?
Young And Beautiful - LANA DEL REY
♪ Hot summer nights, mid-July ♪
你看到整栋房子熠熠生辉的的样子了吗？
See the way the whole front catches the light like that?
噢，太辉煌了
Oh, it's splendid.
♪ When you and I were forever wild ♪
你们两个快跟上，我想来个皇室巡游
Come on, you two. I want the royal tour.
♪ The crazy days, the city lights ♪
你一定知道我喜欢所有现代化的东西
You must understand that I like all things that are modern.
♪ The way you'd play with me like a child ♪
把橙子从这里放进去，橙汁就出来了
Presses the orange it all comes out there.
♪ Will you still love me ♪
♪ when I'm no longer young and beautiful ♪
杰！
Yay!
有人要来盘高尔夫吗？
Anyone for a round of golf?
♪ Will you still love me ♪
- 你应该知道我是个高尔夫冠军吧  - 好极了
- You do know I'm a champion golfer?  - Great!
♪ when I got nothing but my aching soul ♪
好的，继续
Well, go on.
我想我们可以…
I thought we could...
令人惊叹的小相机，最新设计
Remarkable little camera. Latest design.
♪ I know you will, I know you will ♪
我来告诉你怎么玩
I'll show you how it's done.
- 尼克，继续录影  - 好的
- Nick, keep filming.  - All right.
♪ I know that you will ♪
- 她要挥杆了  - 我准备好了
- She's gonna take a swing.  - I'm ready.
瞄准…让开！
Aim. Fore!
♪ Will you still love me ♪
我简直要玩疯了
I'm such a brute.
♪ when I'm no longer beautiful. ♪
- 准备好来张特写了吗？ - 我不想错过任何一个瞬间
- You ready for your close-up?  - I don't want to forget a single moment.
你们看起来太完美了
You're shimmering.
她看起来都能上时尚杂志了
She looks like she could be on the cover of Vogue.
打开相机！
Turn on the camera!
- 你去哪了？ - 慢点
- Where did you go?  - Slow down.
慢点
Slow down.
啊
Ahh.
简直太美了！
It's beautiful.
沃立舍：美国钢琴品牌
- 那是台定制的沃立舍  - 有人会弹钢琴吗？
- It's a custom Wurlitzer.  - Can anyone play that?
尤因·克利普斯普林格会弹，谁去把他叫醒！
Klipspringer can. Someone wake Ewing.
- 好的，先生  - 音乐！
- Of course, sir.  - Music!
然后我们就可以通宵跳舞了
And then we can dance all night.
尤因就是个天才，没有他不会弹的曲子
Ewing's a genius, plays anything.
- 那我来点一首查尔斯顿…  - 她让这里生气勃勃
- Then I demand a Charleston.  - She makes it look so splendid...
♪ ll you still love me ♪
难道不是吗，老兄？
...don't you think, old sport?
♪ when I'm no longer young and beautiful ♪
有个人在英格兰专门负责帮我买衣服
I have a man in England who buys me clothes.
我从来没见过这些
I've never seen anything like it.
♪ Will you still love me ♪
给女士的
Something for the lady.
♪ when I got nothiyg but my aching soul ♪
每年春秋两季开始的时候，他都会挑选一些东西寄给我
He sends over a selection at the beginning of each season.
♪ I know you will, I know you will ♪
这些是丝绸
These are silk.
- 杰！ - 这些是法兰绒
- Jay!  - These are flannel.
它们真是美极了！
They're so beautiful!
♪ I know that you will ♪
印度棉
Indian cotton.
好了，杰！
Stop it. Jay!
亚麻
Linen.
♪ Will you still love me ♪
尼克，他简直疯了！
Nicky, he's a madman!
我可帮不了你！
I can't help you!
♪ when I'm no longer beautiful ♪
法兰绒！
Flannel!
你还得一件一件的重新叠起来！
You're going to have to refold every single one of them.
♪ Will you still love me ♪
你会把它们弄坏的
You'll ruin them!
♪ when I'm no longer beautiful ♪
杰！住手
Jay! Stop it.
- 到这来！ - 不！
- Right here!  - No!
杰！
Jay!
♪ Will you still love me ♪
♪ when I'm no longer young and beautiful. ♪
怎么了？
What is it?
黛西，黛西，亲爱的，怎么了？
Daisy, Daisy, darling, what is it?
我看了心里很难过
It makes me sad.
为什么？
Why?
因为…
Because...
逝去的五年
Five lost years...
黛西终没能说出口
...struggled on Daisy's lips.
她能做的就只有…
But all she could manage was...
为什么？
Why?
因为我从来没见过这么漂亮的衬衫
Because I've never seen such beautiful shirts before.
要不是雾这么大我们可以看到那盏绿灯
If it wasn't for the mist, we could see the green light.
什么绿灯？
What green light?
你家码头那盏一直点到天亮的绿灯
The one that burns all night at the end of your dock.
可能他刚悟到，那盏绿灯以往在他心目中…
Possibly it had occurred to Gatsby that...
所象征的一种不可思议的重要性从今以后要永远消失了
the colossal significance of that light had vanished forever.
现在这件东西现了原形…
Now it was once again...
不过是一盏码头上的绿灯罢了
...just a green light on a dock.
他所憧憬的神奇宝贝又少了一件
And his count of enchanted objects had diminished by one.
这是谁？
Who's this?
- 你父亲吗？ - 噢，不是
- Your father?  - Oh, no.
那是丹·科迪先生，老兄
That's Mr. Dan Cody, old sport.
他已经去世了
He's dead now.
很多年前他是我最好的朋友
He used to be my best friend many years ago.
你从来没告诉过我你头发向后一把梳过…也没告诉过我你家里有游艇
You never told me you had a pompadour. Or a yacht.
我想给你看点东西
I wanna show you something.
请坐
Have a seat.
这里有一大堆剪报…都是关于你的
These are a lot of clippings I collected.About you.
你还留着我的信
You saved my letters.
这是我拥有的你的第一张照片
This was my first photo of you.
你还记得这封信吗？
You remember this letter here?
“我们无法失去彼此，就让这段美好的爱情无疾而终吧…
We can't lose each other. And let all this glorious love into nothing.
…快回来，我在这儿怀着期望等待，期望每一个有你的梦都能成真”
Come home. I'll be here waiting and hoping, for every long dream of you to come true."
失陪
Excuse me.
- 先生，我是底特律的斯莱格尔  - 我现在不方便聊，老兄
- Sir, Slagle's in Detroit.  - I can't talk now, old sport.
难道他连小城都不懂？
He must know what a small town is.
不，你听我说，听我说
No, you listen to me. Listen to me.
我说的是一个小城
I said a small town.
难道他连小城都不懂？
He must know what a small town is.
算了，如果他拿底特律当小城…
Listen to me, he's of no use to us if Detroit is his idea...
那他这个人未免太不中用了…
...of a small town, you understand?
我们晚点再聊，老兄
We'll chat later, old sport.
好的
All right.
克利普斯普林格
Klipspringer.
他一定是醒了
He must be awake.
可以吗？
Shall we?
哇！
Whoo!
哟！
Ho!
我希望我一生中世上所有的事都能跟你一起做
I wish I had done everything on earth with you. All my life...
真希望永远这样下去
I wish it could always be like this.
会的
It Will be.
如果盖茨比仅仅满足于将黛西拥入怀中就好了
If only it had been enough for Gatsby, just to hold Daisy.
但是他却憧憬着和和黛西在一起的生活
But he had a grand vision for his life and Daisy's part in it.
直到那年夏末的一天晚上我见到盖茨比
It wasn't until the end of that summer on the last night I saw Gatsby...
他才告诉我他那从孩提时代就向往的生活
...that he told me of the life he had dreamed for himself since he was a boy.
你看，医生
You see, doctor...
盖茨比的真名叫做杰姆士·盖兹
...Gatsby's real name was James Gatz.
他的父母是北达科他州穷困潦倒的农民
His parents were dirt-poor farmers from North Dakota.
但他未曾真正认他们为亲生父母过
But he never accepted them as his parents at all.
他幻想自己是“天之骄子”，命中注定有着远大的前途
In his own imagination, he was a son of God, destined for future glory.
为了追求未来的光荣，十六岁的盖兹远离故土
Chasing this destiny, a 16-year-old Gatz ran far, far away.
一天下午，他在苏必利尔湖岸发现了一艘处于险境中的游艇
One afternoon, off the coast of Lake Superior, he spotted a yacht in peril.
他划了过去，救了那艘船…
He rowed out and rescued the vessel...
以及船长…酒鬼富翁丹·科迪
...and its captain, alcoholic millionaire Dan Cody.
船在哪里？
Where's the boat?
你会撞在浅滩上的！
You're gonna hit the shoal!
我们会撞在浅滩上的！
We're gonna hit the shoal!
你他妈在干什么…
What the hell are you doing...
…老兄？
...old sport?
这是他的机遇，他把握住了
This was his opportunity and he seized it.
从那以后我就决定改名为杰·盖茨比
And I decided right then and there to call myself Jay Gatsby.
他不仅驾驶游艇脱了险，还开辟了自己的未来
He sailed the yacht out of danger and into his future.
盖茨比充分展现了自己的伶俐和雄心
Gatsby showed skill and ambition.
五年来，他跟着丹·科迪满世界航行
And for five years, they sailed the world.
老丹人很好
He was all right, old Dan.
他什么都教我
He taught me everything.
教我如何穿衣打扮，如何言谈举止像个绅士
How to dress, act and speak like a gentleman.
盖茨比，杰·盖茨比
Gatsby. Jay Gatsby.
她看起来不错，不是吗？
She looks well, doesn't she...
盖茨比希望继承科迪的财产
Gatsby hoped to inherit Cody's fortune.
- 老兄？ - 但是当科迪去世之后
- ...old sport?  - But when Cody died...
盖茨比从丹·科迪那里继承的一小笔钱被他的亲戚们骗了回去
...Gatsby was cheated of his inheritance by Cody's family.
他失去了继续当绅士的资本
He'd been left with the ability to play the gentleman...
再次变得穷困潦倒
...but he was once again dirt-poor.
仲夏之时，盖茨比已成为了新闻头条
By midsummer, Gatsby was front page news.
他的钱是哪来的？
Where did the money come from?
这是所有纽约人都想知道的
That's what all of New York wanted to know.
这同时也是汤姆心中的疑问，自打他…
And it was the same question on Tom's mind...
陪着黛西去参加了一次盖茨比那光鲜的宴会
...when he accompanied Daisy to one of Gatsby's glittering parties.
我一会就回来
I'll be right back.
你知道吗，有很多这样的暴发户实际上都是…
You know, a lot of these newly rich people are just...
- 肮脏的私酒贩子  - 盖茨比可不是
- ...filthy bootleggers.  - Not Gatsby.
他是个商人，他开了很多家药房
He's a businessman. He owned a lot of drugstores.
哼，商人！
Businessman!
给您介绍一下，古利克参议员，这位是…
May I introduce Senator Gulick? This is...
- 卡拉威先生  - 参议员先生
- ...Mr. Carraway.  - Senator.
- 布坎南夫人  - 很迷人
- Mrs. Buchanan.  - Charmed.
谢谢
Delighted.
噢，这位是布坎南先生，马球健将
Oh, and Mr. Buchanan, the polo player.
- 不敢当  - 很荣幸能认识一位布坎南家族的人
- No, not me.  - Always a pleasure to meet a Buchanan.
- 我也一样  - 我一会儿来找你
- Likewise.  - I'll catch up with you later.
- 可能在玩骰子那桌  - 我不是什么马球健将
- Perhaps at the craps table.  - I'd rather not be the polo player.
汤姆，你该为你的成就感到骄傲
Tom. You should be proud of your achievements.
带你们到处看看？
May I show you around?
好的
Sure.
你一定看到许多
You must know the faces...
- 那些你们经常听说过的名流  - 肯定能
- ...of many people you've heard of!  - Absolutely.
我们不经常外出社交，我也许不大能认出哪怕任何一个人
We don't go around very much. I don't think I recognize a single person.
是吗？
...Is that so?
或许你认识那边的那位女士
Perhaps you know that lady right there.
那是马琳·穆恩，我很喜欢她的电影
It's Marlene Moon. I adore her pictures.
需要我来引荐吗？
Would you like me to introduce you?
我宁愿不做马球健将
I'd really rather not be the polo player.
这些简直太让人兴奋了
These things excite me so.
舞也不错
Nice little dance.
我想我们曾经见过面，布坎南先生
I believe we've met before, Mr. Buchanan.
大概一个月前
About a month ago.
是的
That's right.
你当时跟尼克在一起
And you were with Nick here.
- 在理发店  - 不了，谢谢
- At the barbershop.  - No, thank you.
是的
That's right.
看，我认识你太太
See, I know your wife.
是吗？
That so?
是的
Yes.
盖茨比先生
Mr. Gatsby, sir.
- 斯莱格尔先生来了  - 现在不行，不是时候
- Mr. Slagle is here.  - Not now. Not now.
布坎南先生
Mr. Buchanan.
您是否介意我和您太太跳支舞？
Would you mind terribly?
当然不
Of course not.
我想我会自己找乐子的
I think I can keep myself amused.
假如你要写几个住址下来，拿上我的小金铅笔
In case you need to take down any addresses.
请让一下，抱歉
Please move aside. Excuse me.
又一个激情的宴会哦，杰
Another swell party, Jay.
小心蛇妖喔，麦克兰尼汉先生
Be careful for the snake charmer, Mr. McLennehan.
这些都是按你的想象弄的吗？
Is all this made entirely from your own imagination?
不是
No.
是为你量身定做的，我的每一个想法每一个决定都是为你考虑的
You see, you were there all along in every idea in every decision.
当然了，要是有什么你可能不会喜欢，我就会改
Of course, if anything is not to your liking I'll change it.
非常完美…
It's perfect.
拜你那让人无法抗拒的完美想象力所赐
From your perfect irresistible imagination.
我想知道这家伙从哪里认识黛西的
I wonder where the devil he met Daisy.
- 我过会儿去找你  - 好的
- I'll find you.  - All right.
跟我来
Come with me.
请让一让
Coming through, please.
麻烦您
Pardon me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看见我老婆了吗？
Have you seen my wife?
没
No.
有一会没见了
Not for a while.
威士忌
Whiskey.
有意思，参议员先生刚刚还看到她在下面
It's funny, the senator just saw her down here.
真希望我们可以就这样私奔
I wish we could just run away.
私奔？
Run away?
不
No.
黛西，亲爱的，那样…
Daisy, darling, that...
…那样做不体面
...That wouldn't be respectable.
尼克，你住在这附近吗？
You live around here, Nick?
就在隔壁
Just next door.
是吗？
Is that so?
我们留在这儿，住在这幢房子里，我们两个
We're gonna live here. In this house. You and me.
亲爱的
Darling...
是时候告诉汤姆真相了
...it's time to tell Tom.
算了，小伙子们
Come on, boys.
滚开
Scram!
晚安，先生们
Good night, gentlemen.
好一个马戏团啊
What a circus.
呃…要是你看到黛西
Well...if you see her...
麻烦转告她，我在找她
...I'll be looking for her.You tell her.
还记得从前我们在一起有多快乐吗？
Remember how much fun we had?
我不知道我们为什么就不能像那时一样快乐呢？
I don't know why we can't just have fun like that again.
嗨！
Hello?
嗨，尼克
Hello, Nicky.
我们正在吵架
We're having a row.
吵什么？
What about?
一些事情…
About...things.
关于未来
About the future.
有色帝国的未来
The future of the colored empires.
是汤姆
It's Tom.
- 他在宴会上到处找…  - 先生
- He's wandering around the party looking...  - Sir.
盖茨比先生
Mr. Gatsby, sir.
是斯莱格尔先生，他情绪非常激动
It's Mr. Slagle. He's quite emotional.
不好意思
Excuse me.
尼克，如果你不介意的话
Nick. Would you mind terribly?
当然不
Of course.
盖茨比离开去忙他的生意了
Gatsby disappeared to deal with the dispute of some sort.
黛西等啊等…
Daisy waited...
可盖茨比却没有回来
...but Gatsby was unable to return.
热心的人都来了，我信赖你们
With these hot-headed types in here, I rely on you.
但你反而却靠不住，还发生了这种事情
But you were not available. A scene was made.
你最近是怎么一回事，杰？
What's going on with you, Jay?
你去哪儿了？
Where were you?
跟尼克一起，盖茨比先生带我们到庭院里逛了逛
With Nicky. Mr. Gatsby was showing us the grounds.
他就应该跟他的马戏团待在一起
He certainly must have strained himself to get this menagerie together.
我很想知道他到底是谁，究竟是干什么的
I'd like to know who he is and what he does.
不但如此，我要想办法去调查一下
And I think I'll make a point of finding out.
- 我不清楚，问问厨房的人  - 往左边
- I'm not sure. Ask them in the kitchen.  - To the left.
好的
Yeah...
…先把东西堆在车库里，还要回城里的
...we'll pile that stuff in the garage, it's going back to town.
哟，你在这儿啊，黛西刚走
Well...there you are. Daisy just left.
她让我告诉你
She asked me to tell you...
她玩得很开心
...she had a wonderful time.
她并不喜欢
She didn't like it.
她当然喜欢了
Of course she did.
不不不
No, no, no.
不，她不喜欢，她玩得并不开心
No, she didn't like it. She did not have a good time.
我觉得跟她之间有很大的距离
I feel so far away from her now.
很难使她懂我的意思
It's so hard to make her understand.
你是说关于你开宴会的事？
You mean about the party?
宴会？
The party?
其实宴会对于我并不重要
I couldn't care less about the parties.
今天到此为止，先生们
That'll be all for now, gentlemen.
- 谢谢  - 谢谢您，先生
- Thank you.  - Thank you, sir.
她必须去告诉汤姆，她从未爱过他
You see, she has to tell Tom that she never loved him.
什么？
What?
是的
Yes.
然后我们可以一起回她路易斯维尔的家
Then we can go back to Louisville to her parents' house.
她父母都是很好的人，老兄，我们会在那里结婚
Her parents are lovely people, old sport. We'll be married there.
看
See...
你看，黛西和我就会开始我们本该在五年前就开始的生活
See, Daisy and I are gonna start over just as if it were five years ago.
我看还是不要对她要求过分才好
I wouldn't ask too much of her.
不要要求过分？
Wouldn't ask too much?
是的
No.
拜托，老兄，我只是…
I beg your pardon, old sport. It's just...
我只是很难过，因为很难让他懂我…
It's so sad, because it's so hard to make her understand.
让她理解实在太难了
It's so hard to make her understand.
我为她准备了这一切，而她却只想私奔
I've gotten all these things for her, and now she just wants to run away.
她连这一切…
She even wants...
- 都不想要了  - 杰
- ...to leave that.  - Jay.
旧梦不能重温
You can't repeat the past.
不能吗？
Can't repeat the past?
当然不能
No.
为什么，我看可以
Why, of course you can.
当然可以！
Of course you can.
我要把一切事情安排得像从前一样
I'm gonna fix things just the way they were before.
自从我离开她，一切就变得混乱不堪，我…
Everything's been so confused since then. I...
他接着又说了许多关于过去的话
He talked a lot about the past...
好像他想要发现些什么
...as if he wanted to recover something.
如果我能回到事情出发点
If I could just get back to the start...
我就能发现我失去的究竟是什么
...I could find it again.
他以一种自己特有的理解方式爱着黛西
Some vision of himself that he had put into loving Daisy.
五年前，路易斯维尔的一个晚上
One night in Louisville, five years ago...
盖茨比很意外地来到黛西家门口
...Gatsby found himself at Daisy's house by colossal accident.
我起初是跟泰勒军营的其他军官一同去的
GATSBY". I went to her house first with some of the officers from Camp Taylor.
我从未涉足过这样的豪宅
I'd never been in such a beautiful house.
下支舞还能跟你一起跳吗？
May I save the next dance?
他的制服隐藏了他的真实身份…
His uniform hid the truth that...
一个穷困潦倒的年轻人
...he was a penniless young man.
只是看起来是个英武的军官
...with only that grand vision of himself.
- 黛西，不要跑来跑去的  - 我没有，妈妈
- Daisy, don't scamper.  - I was not, Mother.
…这么多身世显赫的年轻军官在这里
So many dashing young officers here. And from such illustrious families.
我坚信我能攀上人生的高峰
I always knew that I could climb.
但前提是我只能单枪匹马勇往直前
But I could only climb if I climbed alone.
我知道我一旦吻了这个女孩子
I knew that when I kissed this girl...
我将会永远沦陷于她
...I would be forever wed to her.
所以我停了下来
So I stopped.
我停下来…等待着
I stopped, and I...I waited.
又等了好久
I waited for a moment longer.
他知道…
He knew...
他的意志再也不会…
...his mind would never again be free to romp like...
无拘无束地驰骋太空了
...the mind of God.
这段爱情
That falling in love...
将会永远地改变他的命运
...would change his destiny forever.
于是我放纵了我自己
And then I just let myself go.
她就像一朵含苞待放的花，为他一瓣一瓣地开放
She blossomed for him like a flower...
而他也就脱胎换骨从此变成另外一个人
...and the incarnation was complete.
像我这样的人陷入爱情的漩涡是一个巨大的错误
I knew it was a great mistake for a man like me to fall in love.
我只有三十二岁，要是我能忘记我曾一度失去黛西的话
I'm only 32. I might still be a great man if I could forget that I once...
我仍然可以成就更辉煌的事业
...lost Daisy, but...
然而，老兄，我的生活…
...my life, old sport, my life...
这才是我想要的生活
My life has got to be like this.
生活总要继续向前看
It's got to keep going up.
黛西必须告诉汤姆，她从未爱过他
She has to go to Tom and tell him that she never loved him.
我要给黛西多一点时间
I just need to give her more time, old sport.
多一点时间
More time.
不要担心，老兄，不要担心
Don't worry, old sport. Don't worry.
在这里有我保护她
I can protect her here.
晚安，老兄
Good night, old sport.
过去的事情并不是你想的那样，老兄
You're wrong about the past, old sport.
你错了
You're wrong.
整个夏天，我邻居家的别墅里总是笙歌不断
There had been music from my neighbor's all summer.
男男女女成群结对出入他的花园
In his blue gardens, men and girls came and went like moths...
伴着星光，他们窃窃私语，笑声不断
...among the whisperings and the laughter and the stars.
早餐
Breakfast.
好的
Yes.
谢谢！谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
笑声
Laughter.
谢谢
Thank you.
不对，“伴着星光，他们窃窃私语，纵情酒色”
No. The whisperings and the champagne and the stars.
但是
But...
在汤姆和黛西离开以后
...after Tom and Daisy's visit...
盖茨比家里的灯光一盏一盏熄灭了
...Gatsby's lights went out one by one.
宴会也没有了
There were no more parties.
黛西有时偷偷地去他家
Daisy visited discreetly.
那在整个夏天都给盖茨比带来愉悦的名望
For the very same fame that had all summer...
如今却成为了他威胁
...been a source of satisfaction to Jay Gatsby, had become a threat.
我不想回家
I don't wanna go home.
听说你把佣人都遣散了？
I hear you fired all your servants.
黛西有时候下午会来我这里
Daisy comes over sometimes in the afternoon.
在我们做出最终决定之前，我不要用会说闲话的人
I wanted people who wouldn't gossip until we decide what we're going to do.
你也知道附近小城都很近，老兄
You see, these towns are very close together, old sport.
要是这事登报了…你明白的
...and, well, it gets in the papers, you understand.
现在的佣人都是吴夫山的人，吴夫山想帮着补贴他们
They're all people Wolfshiem wanted to do something for.
只要他们能烧饭铺床，和之前的佣人又有什么区别？
What's the difference as long as they can cook and make beds, right?
尼克
Nick...
黛西已经准备好了
...Daisy's ready. She's ready.
现在只剩下一件事了
There's just one thing.
她希望你和贝克小姐明天中午去她家用餐
She's requested that you and Miss Baker be there for lunch tomorrow at her house.
你会来的吧，老兄？
Will you come, old sport?
黛西需要你
Daisy needs you.
我也是
I'll
我们都需要你
We need you.
你会来吗，老兄？
Can you come, old sport?
你知道吗？我在哪里看到一篇文章说太阳一年一年下去越来越热
You know, I read somewhere that the sun is getting hotter every year.
不，我说错了
Wait a minute.
正好相反…
It's the opposite.
是说太阳一年一年…
Sun is getting colder...
越变越冷
...every year.
噢，我今天想去海湾那里转转
Oh, I would like to be out on that bay today.
我就住在你家的对面
I'm right across from you.
就在那里
Right there.
是嘛
Oh.
确实是
So you are.
你知道吗，每晚我都能看到你家码头那盏绿灯不停闪烁
You see, every night I can see that light at the end of your dock blinking.
什么灯光？
What light?
呃，布坎南先生
You see, Mr. Buchanan...
我想具体点
...I wanted to be close.
- 黛西和我都  - 太热了
- Daisy and I have both...  - It's so hot!
什么事都是乱七八糟的
Everything's...so confused.
今天下午我们做什么消遣？
What'll we do this afternoon...
今天下午，明天下午，再过三十年下午都做些什么消遣？
...or the day after that, or for the next 3O years?
不要讲这种叫人听了不舒服的话
Oh, don't be morbid.
我想去城里，还有谁想一起去？
Let's go to town. Who wants to go to town?
去城里？
Town?
女人家的脑子里老是这么多花样
Women get these notions.
黛西…
Daisy.
你看起来很酷
You look so cool.
你永远是很酷的样子
You always look so cool...
就像时代广场海报上的绅士一样
...like the advertisement of the man in Times Square.
穿着漂亮衣服的优雅绅士
The man in the cool, beautiful shirts.
她刚才明明告诉了盖茨比她爱他
She had told Gatsby that she loved him.
汤姆·布坎南亲眼看到了
...and Tom had seen.
走吧，我们进城去
Let's go to town.
我非常赞成
I'm perfectly willing.
真是个好主意
It's a marvelous idea.
亨利，备车！
Henri! Have the car brought around now.
这样就去？
Can't anyone at least have...
- 就不能让人先抽根烟？ - 大家吃饭的时候已经抽够了
- ...a cigarette first?  - We smoked through lunch.
走吧，我们开开心心的，大热的天有什么可吵的
Come on, let's have fun. It's too hot to fuss.
黛西，这本来是你的主意
Daisy, it was your great idea.
为什么不呢？大家一起去城里玩吧
Why don't we? Let's all go to town.
我又改变主意了，你个笨蛋
I changed my mind, you brute.
走吧，我们去广场饭店开个套房
Come on. We'll get a great big room at the Plaza...
有一大桶冰块，一大瓶威士忌，很有意思的
...a bucket of ice, a bottle of whiskey, and it will be fun.
别闹了，是你最先开始提出要去城里的
Come on. It was your idea.
好吧，照你说的办
Fine. Have it your own way, Tom.
来吧，乔丹
Come on, Jordan.
你也一起来吧，盖茨比先生？
Will you join us, Mr. Gatsby?
带上两瓶威士忌，包上毛巾
Two bottles of whiskey. Wrap them in a towel.
走啦，尼克！
Come on, Nick!
盖茨比先生
Mr. Gatsby...
要不然你开我的小跑车，让我开你的马戏班花车载其他人进城
...would you be good enough to take my Coupé, and I'll drive everyone else in your circus wagon.
我车里好像汽油不太多，老兄
I don't think there's much gas, old sport.
汽油多得很
No, plenty of gas.
用光了我半路上可以找一个药房停下来再加
Well, if I run out, I'll stop at a drugstore.
这年头药房里什么东西都买得到
...I hear you can buy anything at a drugstore nowadays.
你载上尼克和乔丹
You take Nick and Jordan.
你没问题的
I suppose you can...
- 是的  - 我们广场饭店见
- ...yes.  - We'll meet you at the Plaza.
你要是看见一个嘴里含着两根香烟的男人，那就是我
I'll be the man on the corner smoking two cigarettes!
你们当我是个大傻瓜，是不是？
You must think I'm pretty dumb, don't you?
不过我有时候有一种直觉告诉我应该怎么做
Well, I have a second sight sometimes that tells me what to do.
我已经把这个家伙大致调查了一下
I've made a small investigation into this fellow.
结果你发现他是牛津大学毕业生？
And you found he was an Oxford man?
恐怕是新墨西哥的牛津镇吧
Oxford, New Mexico.
你看看他！身上穿那么一套粉红色的衣服
He wears a pink suit, for chrissake.
汤姆，我们快没油了
Tom, we're almost out of gas.
威尔逊！
Wilson!
你小子等什么呢
What are you waiting for?
- 给我们加点油  - 嗯
- Let's have some gas!  - Uhh.
难道要我自己动手吗？
Do I have to do it myself?
你以为我们停在这里干嘛…看风景吗？
You think I come here to admire the view?
- 不好意思，我病了  - 怎么搞的？
- I'm sorry, I'm sick.  - Why?
- 有什么毛病？ - 我不知道
- Why, what's the matter?  - I don't know.
我近来身体太累了
I'm all run down.
我需要钱
I need money...
- …急着用钱  - 你说什么？
- ...real bad.  - What?
我太太和我想搬到西部去
My wife and I, we wanna go West.
你太太？
Oh, your wife does?
汤姆忽然发生恐慌，心里像油煎一样着急
Tom was feeling the hot whips of panic.
短短一小时前他家有娇妻外有情妇
His mistress and wife...
使他有一种不可侵犯的安全感
...an hour ago so secure...
可是一下子两者眼看都要从他手里溜掉
...were both slipping from his control.
就在这两天让我发现了一桩不正经的事
I wised up to something funny these last two days.
无论她是否心甘情愿，她都要跟我去西部
Yeah, she's going West whether she wants to or not.
汽油多少钱？
What do I owe you?
一美元…
A dollar.
- 呃，一块两毛  - 我可以把那部车卖给你
- $1.20.  - You can have the car.
我明天下午叫车夫开过来！
I'll send it over tomorrow!
够了够了
Okay, fine, fine, fine.
再开一扇窗
Open another window.
没有窗可开了
There aren't any more.
那就打电话叫他们送把斧头上来…
Then telephone for an ax.
最好不要再嚷热了
Will you forget about the heat?
像你这样叽咕只有觉得加倍的热
You make it worse by crabbing about it.
老兄，请你不要找她的错
Why not let her alone, old sport?
你觉得你那句话挺得意的，是吗？
That's a great expression of yours, isn't it?
哪句话？
What is?
张口“老兄”闭口“老兄”的
"Old sport."
- 你是从哪里学来的这一套？ - 喂
- Where'd you pick it up?  - See here.
你要说话打击人，我马上就走
If you're going to make personal remarks I won't stay here a minute.
盖茨比先生
Mr. Gatsby...
我听说你是牛津毕业的
...I understand that you're an Oxford man.
这句话不完全对
No, not exactly, no.
不必客气了，我听说你是上过牛津的
Oh, yes, I understand that you went to Oxford.
- 不错，我是去过那里的  - 好吧
- Well, yes, I went there.  - Sure.
- 穿粉色西装的人竟然上过牛津  - 汤姆
- The man in the pink suit went to Oxford.  - Tom.
我告诉你我是去过的
I said I went there, didn't I?
我听见了，可是我还是要问你是几时去的
Oh, I heard you. I'd like to know when.
你想知道具体时间
You'd like to know when.
是的，盖茨比先生
Well, Mr. Gatsby?
是一九一九那年，我只在那里待了五个月
It was in 1919. I only stayed there five months.
所以我不能说我是牛津毕业的
That's why I can't exactly call myself an Oxford man.
那是停战以后他们为我们一些军官安排的机会
You see, it was an opportunity they gave to some of us officers who fought in the war.
我忍不住要走上去，在他背上拍上一巴掌表示赞许
I wanted to get up and slap Gatsby on the back.
我替你倒杯酒吧，汤姆
I'll make you a drink, Tom.
- 也许喝了酒之后你就不会觉得自己那么蠢  - 且慢
- Then you won't seem so stupid to yourself.  - Wait a minute.
我还要问盖茨比先生一句话
I want to ask Mr. Gatsby one more question.
请尽管问，布坎南先生
Oh, please, please, go on, Mr. Buchanan. Go on.
你跑到我家里来到底是想闹些什么事？
What kind of a row are you trying to cause in my house anyhow?
他并没有闹什么事，是你在这里胡闹，请你表现出一点自制力好不好
He isn't causing a row, you're causing a row. Please have a little self-control.
自制力？
Self-control?
难道现在非得装聋作哑
Oh, I suppose the latest thing is to sit back and...
随便让哪个来历不明的小子跟你太太上床才算时髦
let Mr. Nobody From Nowhere make love to your wife.
哼，如果这样算时髦，就算我守旧吧…
Well, if that's the idea you can count me out.
这年头大家毫无家庭神圣的观念
See, nowadays people begin by sneering at family life and family institutions
再搞下去什么规矩都不守了
...and the next you'll know, we'll throw everything overboard,
黑白之间都可以通婚！
...we'll have intermarriage between black and white!
你太太不爱你
Your wife doesn't love you.
她从来没有爱过你
She never loved you.
她爱的是我
You see, she loves me.
你胡说八道！
You must be crazy.
没有，老兄
No, old sport.
你闲杂知道了吧，她从未爱过你
No, you see, she never loved you.
她当初嫁给你只不过是我没钱
She only married you because I was poor...
她不能老等我，那是她一生的大错
...and she was tired of waiting. It was a terrible...
但是她心里从来没有爱过任何人
...terrible mistake, but in her heart...
只爱我一个人！
In her heart, she never loved anyone but me.
- 我们应该走了  - 咱们还是回去吧
- We should go.  - Let's all go home.
- 坐下，黛西！ - 请坐
- Sit down, Daisy!  - Please.
请坐
Please, take a seat.
坐下吧，黛西
Go on, Daisy.
黛西…
Daisy...
究竟是怎么一回事？
...what's been going on?
- 我要从头到尾听一听  - 我已经告诉你了是怎么一回事
- I want to hear about it.  - I told you what's going on.
已经有五年的事了
It's been going on for five years.
你偷偷跟这家伙来往了五年？
You've been seeing him for five years?
不是来往，我们没法见面
No, no, no, not seeing. Not seeing, we couldn't. But...
可是我们俩在这段时期彼此相爱，难道不是吗？
...both of us loved each other all that time. Didn't we?
哦，原来不过如此
Oh, that's all.
哈哈哈，你简直发疯了！
Ha-ha-ha! You're crazy!
五年前的事我管不了那么多
I can't speak about what happened five years ago
因为那时我还没认识黛西…
...because I didn't know Daisy then.
可是打死我也猜不出你怎么会有机会跟她接近
And I'll be damned if I see how you got within a mile of her...
除非你是上她家后门送菜的
...unless you brought the groceries to the back door.
至于你其余的话都是放狗屁
But all the rest of that is a goddamn lie.
黛西嫁给我的时候她是爱我的…
Daisy loved me when she married me.
- 现在她还爱我  - 他不爱你
- ...and she loves me now.  - No.
- 很抱歉，布坎南先生，她不爱你  - 随你怎么说，她还是爱我
- No. I'm sorry, Mr. Buchanan, no.  - She does! She does, though.
随你怎么说，她爱我
No, she does, though.
她爱着我，并且我也同样爱着黛西
She does. And what's more, I love Daisy too.
不是的
No.
我爱你，黛西
I love you, Daisy.
我有时也爱逢场作戏
Now, once in a while...
可是事后我总是会回来
...I go off on a spree. I always come back.
- 逢场作戏，哼  - 我心里始终还是爱着黛西
- A spree.  - And in my heart I love her all the time.
不要叫人恶心吧
You're revolting.
你知道我们为什么不得不离开芝加哥？
You know why we left Chicago?
我很奇怪没有人告诉你…
I'm surprised they didn't treat you...
那一次他逢场作戏闹到什么田地！
...to the story of that little spree!
黛西，那些旧事不必再提，亲爱的，都过去了
That's all over now, Daisy, darling. That's all over.
不用多说，就跟他讲真话…
Just tell him the truth. Go on.
告诉他你从来没爱过他…其他的事也就一笔勾销
That you never loved him and this will all be wiped out forever.
我从前怎么可能爱他？
How could I love him...
- 怎么可能…  - 按计划来
- ...possibly?  - Remember our plans.
告诉他你从来没爱过他
You tell him that you never loved him and all...
痛苦就永远结束了
...this pain will be wiped out forever.
黛西
Daisy.
黛西，快说
Daisy, tell him.
我从来没有爱过他
I never loved him.
从来都没有吗
Never?
- 没有  - 没有
- No.  - No.
记得我们一同到夏威夷逛加比奥兰里的时候，你没有爱过我吗？
Not at Kapiolani?
记得那次我从“酒钵”火山口把你抱下来不让你鞋子弄湿，你那时没爱我吗？
Not that day I carried you down from the Punch Bowl to keep your shoes dry?
从来没有吗？
Never?
请别继续说下去了
Please don't.
黛西
Daisy.
你看，杰
There, Jay.
你的要求太过分了
You want too much.
我现在我爱你
I love you now...
这还不够吗？
...isn't that enough? I can't help...
过去的事我没办法改
...what's past.
我从前一度是爱过他的…但是我一直也爱着你
I did love him once, but I loved you too.
你也一直在爱我？
You loved me too?
你也一直在爱我？其实连这个都是瞎话！
You loved me...? Even that is a lie!
她嫁给我以后根本忘掉有你这么个人
She didn't know you were alive!
告诉你…
There are things between Daisy and me...
黛西跟我之间有些事你一辈子也不会知道
...Gatsby, that you'll never know.
- 我们一辈子也不会忘记  - 我想要跟黛西…
- Things that neither of us can ever forget.  - I need to...
单独说一句话
...speak to Daisy alone.
你瞧，你把她搞得紧张过度…
You see, you've got her all excited now, don't you...
- 老兄？ - 跟你单独说话…
- ...old sport? Daisy.  - Even alone...
我也不能说我从来没爱过汤姆，我即使那么说也不是真心话
...I can't say I never loved Torn. It wouldn't be true.
- 什么？ - 当然不是真心话
- What?  - Of course it wouldn't.
- 你这个人还在乎？ - 我当然在乎！
- As if it mattered to you.  - Of course it matters!
从今天起我要好好照顾你
I'm gonna take better care of you from now on.
你还是不懂，你没有机会再照顾她了
You're not taking care of Daisy anymore. She's leaving you.
胡说八道
Nonsense!
- 我是准备要离开你  - 不，不可能
- I am, though!  - No, no, no.
她不会离开我！
She is not leaving me.
无论如何不会为了一个小拆白党离开我
Certainly not for a common swindler like you.
盖茨比先生，你到底是谁？
Mr. Gatsby, exactly who are you, anyhow?
我已经调查了一些你的秘密
I made an investigation into your affairs.
你是迈尔·吴夫山的那帮群狗党
You're one of Meyer Wolfsheim's bunch.
我们还是回家吧
Please, let's go home.
他跟这个吴夫山盘下许多的药房
See, he and this Wolfshiem, they bought up drugstores.
然后在柜台偷卖私酒
And sold bootlegged alcohol over the counter.
那又怎样，老兄？
What about it, old sport?
别叫我“老兄”！
Don't you call me "old sport."
药房的勾当跟债券操盘业务比起来不过是小意思
And this drugstore business is just small change compared to this bonds stunt
就是你和吴夫山经营的生意
...that you and Wolfshiem have got going.
你的朋友沃尔特·蔡斯
Your friend Walter Chase...
不也过来跟我们合伙了吗？
...isn't too proud to come in?
像沃尔特·蔡斯这样声名卓著的银行家
How does a reputable banker like Walter Chase find himself
怎么会债台高筑？
...up to his eyeballs in debt...
- 让我告诉你  - 欠吴夫山那么多钱？
- I'll tell you.  - ...to a little kike like Wolfshiem?
- 那是因为他自己贪婪，老兄  - 好吧
- It's called greed, old sport.  - That's right!
每周末都有大批金融界人士
And you have half of Wall Street out there swilling your...
在你家花园里开怀畅饮，寻欢作乐
...free booze at that fun park every weekend.
我还很奇怪他为什么没有拉你如伙
I'm surprised he hasn't tried to drag you in.
呵呵，你早就加入他们了
My God, he has.
跟他没有关系
He's got nothing to do with...
跟你过着花天酒地的生活
With your little racket.
黛西
Daisy.
难道你还没有看清楚这个道貌岸然的家伙…
Can't you see who this guy is...
和他那别墅、宴会的真面目吗？
...with his house and his parties and his fancy clothes?
他只是吴夫山的朋党
He is just a front for Wolfshiem, a gangster...
一个连沃尔特·蔡斯这样的良民也要陷害的人
...to get his claws into respectable folk like Walter Chase.
老兄，你唯一值得人尊敬的也只是你的钱…
The only respectable thing about you, old sport, is your money.
你的金钱，仅此而已，现在我跟你一样富有，我们没有什么区别
Your money, that's it. Now I've just as much as you. That means we're equal.
哦，不不
Oh, no. No.
我们是不同的
We're different.
我跟你不一样
I am.
他们
They are.
还有她
She is.
我们都跟你是不一样的
We're all different from you.
你瞧，我们的出身完全不同
You see, we were born different.
这是根植在我们的血液里面的东西
It's in our blood...
无论你做什么，怎么粉饰、怎么窃取，怎么梦寐以求…
...and ain't nothing that you do or say or steal...
都无法改变你的出身
...or dream up can ever change that.
像黛西这样的女孩
A girl like Daisy...
闭嘴！
You shut up!
闭嘴
Shut up!
你给我闭嘴，闭嘴！
You shut up! Shut up!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
盖茨比看起来就像“刚杀死了人”的样子
Gatsby looked, in that moment as if he had killed a man.
我表示最诚挚的歉意
My sincerest...My sincerest apologies.
我刚刚确实有些失态…
I seem to have lost my temper.
那就对了，盖茨比先生
That's right, Mr. Gatsby.
这才像牛津毕业生的教养
Show us some of those fine Oxford manners.
黛西，亲爱的
Daisy, darling.
他说的这些都没什么大不了的
None of this has any consequence.
黛西
Daisy.
黛西，亲爱的，说话啊
Daisy, talk to me, darling.
我刚刚有点失控，仅此而已
I just lost my temper, that's all.
他开始激动地说话
He began talking excitedly,
但是他话越说得多，黛西越显得疏远
...but with every word Daisy was drawing further and further into herself.
…去你在路易斯维尔的父母家
...to go to your parents' house in Louisville.
汤姆，我求求你，我实在受不了啦！
Please, Tom, I can't stand it anymore!
你们两人先回去，黛西
Why don't you two start on home...
坐盖茨比先生的车去
...in Mr. Gatsby's car.
- 黛西，亲爱的，看着我  - 你尽管跟他走
- Daisy, darling, look at me.  - Go on.
黛西
Daisy.
他不敢对你有什么无礼的举动
He won't annoy you.
我想他心里明白…
I think he realizes...
- 他那想吃天鹅肉的白日梦已经破灭了  - 黛西？
- ...that this little flirtation is over.  - Daisy?!
黛西！
Daisy!
要喝一杯吗？
You want any of this?
乔丹？尼克？
Jordan? Nick?
尼克？
Nick.
什么？
What?
要来一杯吗？
You want any?
不要了
No.
我刚记起来
I just remembered...
今天是我生日
...today's my birthday.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
人生有几个三十岁…眼前保不住再来十年孤寂的生活
Thirty. The promise of a decade of loneliness.
随着盖茨比和黛西在微凉的暮色中…
The formidable stroke of 30 died away...
驶向死亡
...as Gatsby and Daisy drove on through the cooling twilight...
三十岁带来的冲击就这么消逝了
...towards death.
别骗我！
Don't you lie to me!
你是从哪里搞到的？
Hey, where'd you get these from?
你骗的了我，但是你骗不了上帝
You might fool me, but you don't fool God!
上帝都看在眼里！
God sees everything!
梅朵！
Myrtle!
你在哪？
Where are you?
汤姆？
Tom?
梅朵！
Myrtle!
我在这，停车！
I'm here! Stop!
宝贝！
Baby!
汤姆！
Tom!
停一下！
Wait!
慢点
Slow down.
慢点！
Slow down!
前边出事了，先生
Bad trouble up ahead, sir!
不错，威尔逊终于有一点生意了
Good. Wilson'll have a little business at last.
我们去看一眼
Let's take a look.
我们还是走吧
Oh, must we?
看一眼就走
Just a look.
来吧
Come on.
往后面走，把地方腾开！
Move back! Clear the space here!
有点尊重好不好！
Have a little respect!
请闲杂人等都出去！
If you don't have a legitimate reason to be in the building I want you outside!
如果你们刚刚看见什么了的话请告诉我
If you saw anything tonight you'd like to talk to me about, well, then you can...
我们出去谈
...talk to me outside.
你们都出去，好吗！
I don't want you in here. Okay?
请往后走走
Please. Stand back. Please.
上帝啊
My God.
好了老兄们
All right, folks.
大家都往后，大家都往后！
Make some room, huh? Make some room back there!
要是没事的话，请把地方腾开！
If you have no business, clear out!
先生
Sir.
你有什么事吗？先生！
What are you doing? Sir!
先生，请你…
Sir, I'm asking you...
别碰我
Get off me!
我很好
I'm fine.
我没事
你认识她吗？
You knew her, eh?
呃…不认识
Not really. No.
那么请你往后面走
I gotta ask you to step back, sir.
发生了什么事情？
So, what happened?
她突然跑到路中间
She ran out in the road.
- 那个混蛋的车子停都没停  - 嘿
- Son of a bitch didn't even stop his car.  - Hey.
我看见了，那是一辆黄色的车子
I saw it. It was a yellow car.
黄色的大汽车
A big yellow car.
不知道是从哪里窜出来的
Damn thing came out of nowhere.
是的，是的，一辆黄色的跑车，手工打造
Yeah. Yeah, a big yellow Duesy. Custom job.
不用告诉我那车是什么样的！我知道那部车是什么样子！
You don't have to tell me what kind of car it was.
我知道那部车是什么样子！
I know what kind of car it was.
威尔逊
Wilson.
- 你一定要想办法撑住  - 我知道那部车是什么样子！
- Just pull yourself together!  - I know what kind of car it was!
他太伤心了！大家都出去！
He's upset! Everybody out!
难道看不出来他需要安静吗！
Can't you see the man needs peace and quiet?
威尔逊，我这会儿刚从纽约赶到
Wilson! I just got here from New York.
别这样，嘿，威尔逊！
No! Hey! Wilson!
我是要把你想买的那辆小跑车开来给你的
I was bringing you the coupé.
坐下来，坐下！
Sit down! Sit down.
给他拿点水来！
Get him a drink. Get him a drink.
那部黄色的车子不是我的！
That yellow car wasn't mine!
听清楚了吗？
You hear? I haven't...
- 我后来就没再开  - 嘿！
- ...seen it all afternoon.  - Hey!
你的车子什么颜色
What color's your car?
蓝色的
It's blue.
跑车
Coupé.
我们刚从纽约开到这儿
We just got here from New York.
他们刚刚才停下的
They just stopped!
好吧
0K.
蓝色
Blue.
好的
Right.
这里
Here.
让我们呆一会
Leave us alone.
威尔逊
Wilson.
那是谁的车子
Who owns the yellow car?
一个叫盖茨比的家伙
A fella named Gatsby.
杰·盖茨比
Jay Gatsby.
他是个骗子，威尔逊
He's a crook, George.
报纸上说的那个老是开宴会的家伙
Yes. Throws those parties the papers are always talking about.
也许就是他在跟梅朵鬼混
Maybe he was the one that was fooling around with Myrtle.
可能他就是因为这个原因杀了梅朵
Maybe that's why he killed her.
很可能
Yeah, maybe.
他这样的人，哼，谁知道呢？
Guy like that, who knows?
他也没必要杀了她啊？
He didn't have to kill her.
盖茨比
Gatsby.
他会有报应的
Something ought to be done about a fella like that.
他必须付出代价
He'll pay.
是的，血债血偿
Oh, he'll pay.
没种的畜生！
Coward.
他连车子都不停一下！
He didn't even stop his car.
你们还要替他说话吗
You gonna defend him now?
啊哈？
Huh?
我打电话给你叫辆车，尼克
I'll telephone for a taxi, Nick.
等车的同时顺便进来吃点东西吧？
Why don't you come inside and have some supper while you wait?
不了，谢谢，我就在外面等吧
No, thanks. I'll wait outside.
你这是…
What is the matter...
怎么一回事？
...With you?
进来坐一会儿，尼克？
Won't you come in, Nick?
不了，谢谢
No, thanks.
时候还早，才九点半
It's only half past 9.
不了，我受够你们了
No, I've had enough.
你们每个人
Of everyone.
嗨，老兄
Hello, old sport.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing?
没什么，就在这坐一会儿
Just sitting here.
我知道
Yes, I see that.
你回来的时候有没有在路上看到出了什么事？
You see any trouble out on the road?
那个女人吗？
That woman...
- 你把她撞死了，杰  - 我当时就知道撞死了
- ...you ran down is dead, Jay.  - I thought so.
我告诉黛西一定是撞死了
I told Daisy that I thought so.
黛西？你知道你说了些什么吗！
Daisy? Do you hear yourself?
你怎么可以！
How could you?
你怎么可以这么做！
How could you do that?
你小声点
Keep your voice down.
你是…
You're nothing...
- 是个杀千刀的懦夫！ - 小点声！
- ...but a goddamn coward!  - Keep your voice down!
请听我解释，当时根本来不及…
Please. There was no point in stop...
来不及？来不及？那个女人怎么办！
No point'? No point? What about that woman?
我没办法，她当场就撞死了
No point. She was killed instantly.
人都被你撞开花了，我都看见了，我看见了！
Yes, it ripped her open! I was there! I saw her!
我知道，我都知道，是我的错
I understand! I understand! It was my fault.
我的错，这个女人…
It was my fault. This woman...
她从路旁冲出来，好像是要拦住我们说话
...she rushed out at us as if she was trying to speak to us.
一切发生得太快，她本来想刹车…然后我…
It all happened so quickly. She tried...I tried...
- 伸手想夺过方向盘…  - “她”？
- ...to turn in time...  - "She"?
但是…
...but...
开车的是黛西
It was Daisy.
呃，是的，我…
Well, I...
我们离开纽约的时候她神经很紧张
You see, after we left New York, she was very nervous.
她以为开开车子可以让她镇定下来
She thought that driving would steady her.
想不到这个女人突然从路旁冲出来
But this woman, she rushed out at us.
突然之间就发生了
It all happened so quickly.
不是黛西的错
It wasn't her fault...
你明白吗？
...do you see?
不能让任何人知道是黛西开的车
No one must know that Daisy was driving.
答应我
Promise me.
杰，你应该回家好好休息休息
Jay, you should go home and get some rest.
我要在这等着
I'm going to wait here. I'm going to wait here all night...
- 直等到天亮，如果需要的话  - 不不
- ...if necessary.  - No, no, no.
- 没这个必要的  - 要是他因为今天下午吵架的事
- That's not a good idea.  - If he tries...
让黛西为难
...to bother her about that unpleasantness this afternoon...
要是他敢动她
If he tries to bother her...
要是他敢有什么野蛮的举动…
If he tries any brutality on her whatsoever...
汤姆不会碰她的，他现在满脑子想的都不是她
Tom won't touch her. He's not even thinking about her.
我不信任这家伙
I don't trust him.
- 我不相信他  - 没事的
- I don't trust him.  - All right.
没事的
All right.
你在这里等着
You wait here.
我去看看有什么动静
I'll see if there's any commotion.
真的吗？
Would you?
谢谢你，老兄
Thank you, old sport.
听着，是她自己跑出来的，是她自己的错
Listen, she was in the wrong, running out on the road.
亲爱的
Sweetheart, you have...
你不必如此担心
...nothing to worry about.
让我来处理
Let me take care of things.
照顾好自己
Take care of you.
我会打几个电话
I'll make some calls.
我们离开这里
We'll go away.
离开纽约，远走高飞
Just go away, get out of town.
好好休息一下，不用担心
Get some rest. Don't worry.
一切都会过去
It'll be all right.
嗨，老兄
Oh. Hello, old sport.
- 都还好吧？ - 是的
- Everything all right?  - Yes.
都很好
Everything's just fine.
我一直等到四点，看到她走到窗口
Around 4:00, she came to the window.
站了一会儿，然后把灯熄掉
She stood there, then she turned out the light.
然后…
So...Well...
能帮我个忙吗，老兄？
Give me a hand, will you, old sport?
我应该我所见的全部告诉他，但是最终我却说的是…
I should have told him what I had just seen, but all I could manage was:
杰，既然事情已经发生了
You know, Jay, with everything that's happened...
你应该离开这里
...you ought to go away.
今晚就走，他们就会来查你的车子
Tonight. They'll trace your car.
离开这里？不行，我不能现在就走
Go away? No, I can't leave now.
至少今晚不行
Not tonight.
杰，你明白吗，一个女人出车祸死了
Jay, do you understand that a woman has been killed?
黛西今早会给我打电话的
Daisy's going to call in the morning.
然后我们再计划一起远走高飞
Then we'll make plans to go away together.
- 好吧  - 黛西，她…
- Yeah.  - Daisy, she...
她需要时间好好想想…赫尔佐格…
She just needs time to think things through. Herzog...
我们正在谈话，谢谢
...we're talking. Thank you.
她只是需要时间来考虑
She just needs time to think.
不，杰，跟黛西的事…
No, Jay. With Daisy...
她只是需要时间，她今早会打电话来的
She just needs time to think. She's going to call in the morning.
陪我一会吧
Wait up with me.
天就快亮了
The sun's almost up.
就是那晚我们俩黑夜对坐的时候，他告诉了我他的传奇故事
That was the night he finally told me the truth.
关于他的一切
All of it.
我想了很久
You know, I've thought for a while...
我拥有了很多东西，但我还是感到空虚…
...I had a lot of things, but the truth is I'm empty.
这也是我精心粉饰自己的原因
I suppose that's why I make things up about myself.
我打算花很长时间把我所有的故事都告诉你
But I've wanted to tell you the whole story for a very long time.
我成长于一个穷困潦倒的家庭，老兄
See, I grew up terribly, terribly poor, old sport.
- 我的家人都…  - 他从他卑微的出身讲起
- My folks were...  - He revealed his humble beginnings...
他和丹·科迪的航海经历、战争生涯、牛津岁月…
...his transformative voyage with Dan Cody...the war...Oxford...
还有他怎么参与了吴夫山的生意
...and how he joined Wolfshiem in the business.
就在那个晚上，我发现盖茨比身上有一种天赋
It was also that night...
那是一种异乎寻常的、天赋的乐观
...that I became aware of Gatsby's extraordinary gift for hope.
我无法形容当我发现自己爱上了她的时候，我有多么惊讶
I can't describe how surprised I was to find out that I loved her.
当然，她也爱我
And that she loved me too.
这种天赋我从未在别人身上发现过…
A gift that I have never found in any other person.
我从来没有想到一位大家闺秀能有多么不寻常
I never realized how extraordinary a nice girl could be.
以后也绝不会发现了
And which it is not likely I shall ever find again.
我想象着和黛西在一起的生活
I thought out my life with Daisy in it...
想象着我们怎么才能结婚，如何为生计奔波
...trying to figure out how we could marry and struggle along on so many dollars a month.
你的信里写了什么？
What was in the letter?
我战后没能回来的原因
The reason why after the war I hadn't been able to return.
我请她等我成就一番事业，但她…
I asked her to wait until I made something of myself, but she was...
我觉得我们已经在一起了
See, I felt married to her.
就这样
That was all.
这些都是为黛西准备的
It was all for her.
别墅，宴会
The house, the parties.
所有的东西
Everything.
上天把一切都看在眼里
God sees everything.
盖茨比先生
Mr. Gatsby, sir, excuse me.
芝加哥的电话
Chicago calling, sir.
现在不行
Not now.
保持线路畅通，等私人电话
Keep it open for a personal call.
盖茨比先生，我打算把游泳池的水放掉
Mr. Gatsby, I'm gonna drain the pool.
赶在树叶掉到里面之前
Before the leaves start falling in.
今天不行
Not today.
不要在今天弄，池子多漂亮
Not today, it's so beautiful.
你知道，老兄，我整个夏天都没用过那个游泳池，我们一起游个泳吧
You know, old sport, I haven't used that pool once all summer. Let's take a swim.
把电话拿过来吧
Have the phone brought down to the pool.
我要走了，杰
I have to go, Jay.
我必须去工作了
I have to work.
我理解
I understand.
好吧，我送你出去
Well...I'll walk you out.
我会给你打电话的
Well, I'll call you up.
一定，老兄
Please do, old sport. Please do.
我想黛西也会给我打电话的
I supposed that Daisy will call too.
我想会的
I suppose.
是的
Yes.
再会
Well, goodbye.
杰！
Jay!
他们都是混蛋！
They're a rotten crowd.
他们没有一个人比得上你！
You're worth the whole damn bunch put together.
我很高兴我说了那句话
I was always glad I said that.
那是我唯一一次恭维他
It was the only compliment I ever paid him.
那个早晨的华尔街像以往一样繁荣
That morning Wall Street boomed its usual golden roar.
但是我委实配不上这份工作
But I wasn't worth a decent stroke of work.
我一直在等盖茨比的消息
I waited for Gatsby to call with news.
他却一直在等待黛西的电话
While he waited for Daisy.
盖茨比公馆
Gatsby's.
你能来电话盖茨比先生一定会很开心的
I know Mr. Gatsby will be very happy that you've called.
黛西
Daisy.
怎么了，怎么了？
Hello! Hello!
发生什么事了？
Hello! ls everything all right?
有人吗，有人吗？
Hello! Hello!
发生什么事了？
Hello! ls everything all right?
我记得那天只有一批一批的警察、
I remember the rest of that day as an endless drill...
摄影师和新闻记者
...of police and photographers and tabloid reporters.
报纸上的新闻简直像一场噩梦
The headlines were a nightmare.
铺天盖地都是盖茨比的事情
They pinned everything on Gatsby.
他和梅朵的风流事、撞车逃逸以及所有的事情
The affair with Myrtle. The hit-and-run. Everything.
我什么都说不出来，除了一个难以言说的事实…
And there was nothing I could say...
报道上的一切都是假的
...except the one unutterable fact that none of it was true.
亲爱的，爸爸会照顾好我们两个的
Darling, Daddy's taking care of his two favorite girls.
我们要去哪里呀？
Where are we going?
- 我们去度假  - 我们该出发了
- We're going on a holiday.  - We should go.
只有我们一家三口的度假
Just you me and Daddy.
布坎南公馆
Buchanan residence.
我能跟布坎南夫人说句话吗？
May I speak to Mrs. Buchanan?
我是卡拉威，她的表哥
It's Mr. Carraway, her cousin.
夫人现在不方便接电话，卡拉威先生
HENRY. Madame is not available, Monsieur Carraway.
如果可以的话，请你告诉黛西，葬礼在明天举行
If you speak to her, tell her the funeral's tomorrow.
对不起，先生，他们已经走了
I'm sorry, monsieur, they have gone away.
走了？
Gone away?
你知道他们什么时候回来吗？
Do you know when they'll be back?
不知道
No.
他们已经离开了
They have already departed.
请你告诉黛西，我知道她会去的…
Please. I know that she would want to be there. She would...
请把葬礼的消息告诉她
If you would just get a message to her.
- 让我跟黛西说句话  - 你真想联系她吗？
- Let me talk to her, please.  - You wish to contact her?
我也不清楚，先生
I have no further information, monsieur.
喂？
Hello?
走吧
Come on.
汤姆和黛西，他们这班人都是粗心的
They were careless people, Tom and Daisy.
他们砸碎了东西、撞死了人
They smashed up things and people...
然后缩回到自己的钱堆和漫不经心的无所谓当中
...and then retreated back into their money and their vast carelessness.
嗨
Hey-
都出去！
Hey! Get out of here!
快点！
Go on!
都滚出去！
Get the hell out of here!
我打电话…
I rang...
写信…
...I wrote...
不断的求人
...I implored.
千百个得了他好处的人之中
But not a single one of the sparkling hundreds that enjoyed his hospitality...
居然没有一个来参加他的葬礼
...attended the funeral.
黛西连一朵花都没送
And from Daisy not even a flower.
我是他唯一的朋友
I was all he had.
唯一关心他的人
The only one who cared.
盖茨比死后纽约在我心目中就是这样鬼影憧憧
After Gatsby's death New York was haunted for me.
这座城市…
That city...
这个我曾经追逐黄金梦的地方
...my once golden shimmering mirage...
如今却让我厌恶
...now made me sick.
在我离开纽约之前的最后一晚
On my last night in New York
我走过去向那座庞大的、象征失败的房子
...I returned to that huge...
做最后一次巡礼
...incoherent house once more.
吴夫山的人拿走了一切
Wolfshiem's associates had cleaned it out.
他摆出这样阔绰的场面，指望哪天晚上她可能也会来他家参加一次宴会
He threw all those parties hoping she'd wander in one night.
这里就像一个游乐场一样
It's like an amusement park.
你是怎么样一个人生活的
But how do you live here all alone?
她让这里生气勃勃
She makes it look so splendid...
你说呢，老兄？
...don't you think, old sport?
音乐！然后我们就可以通宵跳舞了
Music! And then we can dance all night!
你会来吗，老兄？
Will you come, old sport?
我们需要你
We need you.
要是能一直这样该多好
I wish it could always be like this.
会的
It Will be.
我忆起我初次去他家的情形，我们一个个都在揣想他的背景是多么龌龊
I remembered how we had all come to Gatsby's and guessed at his corruption...
而他本人站在我们面前
...while he stood before us...
心里蕴藏着他纯洁的梦
...concealing an incorruptible dream.
一切都太完美了
It's perfect. From your perfect, irresistible imagination.
夜幕渐渐降临
The moon rose higher.
我站在那儿，一面思潮回到那古老、既失的世界
And as I stood there, brooding on the old, unknown world...
一面想到盖茨比第一次认出对岸黛西那盏绿灯的时候
...I thought of Gatsby's wonder...
一定也有同等的惊奇
...when he first picked out the green light at the end of Daisy's dock.
他好不容易历尽甘苦
He had come such a long way.
他的梦想似乎近在眼前
And his dream must have seemed so close...
一伸手就可以掌握
...that he could hardly fail to grasp it.
他所不知的是
But he did not know...
他所追求的早已丢在了背后
...that it was already behind him.
盖茨比一生的信念就寄托在这盏绿灯上
Gatsby believed in the green light...
对于他，这代表着未来的极乐仙境…虽然这个目标一年一年在我们眼前往后退
...the orgastic future that year by year recedes...
我们从前追求时曾经扑过空，不过没关系…
It eluded us then, but that's no matter.
明天我们会跑得更快一点
Tomorrow, we will run faster...
两手伸得更远一点…
...stretch out our arms farther...
总有一天…
...and one fine morning...
原著结尾，也是菲茨杰拉德夫妇的墓志铭
于是我们继续往前挣扎
So we beat on,
像逆水中的扁舟
...boats against the current,
被浪头不断向后推
...borne back ceaselessly into the past.
盖茨比
了不起的
谢谢观赏
翻译&制作｜四狗@豆瓣  @i_am_the_engineer
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者